<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A mild, but searching expostulatory letter from the poor and plain-dealing farmers of the neighbouring villages to the men of Buckingham to the Right Worshipful the Bailiff, the Worshipful the Burgesses of the ancient, and sometimes famous corporation of Buckingham.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1680</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 124 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 36 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A50846</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing M2039</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R16570</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13033203</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 13033203</idno>
            <idno type="VID">96794</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A50846)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 96794)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 745:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A mild, but searching expostulatory letter from the poor and plain-dealing farmers of the neighbouring villages to the men of Buckingham to the Right Worshipful the Bailiff, the Worshipful the Burgesses of the ancient, and sometimes famous corporation of Buckingham.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet (2 p. in double columns).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1680?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Broadside.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Signed at end: S.T., R.W. etc.</note>
                  <note>"On a late election of Members of Parliament in which the Burgh is said to have acted illegally. The letter is most abusive in tone and foul in language." Cf. Crawford, J.L.L. Cat. of Engl. broadsides, 174.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  London --  17th century</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-03</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <group>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <body>
               <div type="letter">
                  <pb facs="tcp:96794:1"/>
                  <pb n="1" facs="tcp:96794:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <head>A MILD, but SEARCHING EXPOSTULATORY LETTER From the Poor and Plain-dealing Farmers of the Neighbouring Villages, To the <hi>MEN</hi> of <hi>B<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>CKINGHAM.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <head type="sub">To the Right Worſhipful the <hi>Bailiff,</hi> the Worſhipful the <hi>Burgeſſes</hi> of the Ancient, and ſometimes Famous Corporation of <hi>B<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>CKINGHAM.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>Right Worſhipful, and Worſhipful Gentlemen!</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>IF your late Folly and Madneſs had only a Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lignant Influence upon your Unworthy ſelves, we could contentedly have left you Fools and Madmen at your own Coſts and Charges; Had you betray'd your own Liberties, whilſt ours had been ſecure, or ſold your Selves and Poſterities for Slaves, whilſt We and Ours had remained free, We love you ſo well, you might have been eternally ſuch, without any the leaſt Lett, Moleſtation, or Diſtur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bance from Us your poor Neighbours. Nay, had you put Fire to your own Houſes, whilſt ours had been out of the reach of your Flames, or purchaſed ſome dreadful Plague, whoſe Chain-ſhot might have <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>own you down by Whole-ſale, whilſt we were out of the compaſs of its Contagion, we could be ſilently unconcern'd, nor have grudg'd you that Vaſſallage and Deſolation, which we confeſs you have highly merited, and you muſt confeſs you had drawn with your own Hands upon your own Heads.</p>
                  <p>But ſeeing the Frame and Conſtitution of our Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liaments is ſuch, that the Knights of one County, the Citizens of one City, the Burgeſſes of one Burrough, muſt Debate, Vote, Reſolve and Enact what all the Counties, all the Cities, all the Boroughs of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom are concern'd in, and oblig'd by, that we muſt pay the reckoning, which your Folly has inflamed; that we muſt be ſick of your Drunkenneſs, that your Prodigals muſt be prodigal out of our Purſes, and what was your particular, and Perſonal Miſcarriage, muſt (if other Electors had no more Wit and Hone<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty than your ſelves) become a General and National Miſery; give us leave, (or elſe we muſt take it) to correct you gently, and repreſent to you plainly and impartially, your abominable Treachery to our Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Intereſt, in your late ſhameful Election of Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers to ſerve in the enſuing Parliament.</p>
                  <p>It is not We, your deſpiſed Neighbours, 'tis not this County, but all the Counties, Cities, and Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>roughts of the Land (except a few of the ſame ſordid and baſe Spirits with your ſelves) in whoſe Name, and at whoſe Suit we have drawn up this Legal In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictment againſt your illegal and riotous Election; <hi>That you the Mercenary and Debauched Bailiff, with the corrupt Majority of your Brethren, the Burgeſſes of the Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rough of</hi> Buckingham, <hi>not having the Fear of God before your Eyes, but being led by the infligation of the Devil, the Duty and Allegiance which to your Native Countrey you owe, forgetting, and not in any wiſe regarding, have Wickedly, Devilliſhly, and of your own Malice, fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thought, betrayed your Truſt, and as much as in you <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>h, endeavoured to deſtroy thoſe Natural and inherent Rights, thoſe Fundamental Liberties and Privileges, which all free-born</hi> Engliſhmen <hi>have, and of Right ought to enjoy; and in order to, and in purſuance of this your Trayterous, Accurſed, and Helliſh Deſign, have elected ſuch Perſons to Repreſent you, and ſerve for you in the Houſe of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons, as are notoriouſly known to have formerly betrayed the Truſt repoſed in them, and have thereby expoſed the whole Kingdom to the apparent Danger and viſible Haz<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zard of Beggary, Slavery, and Popery.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>Now ſuffer us to expoſtulate the Caſe with you in all Meekneſs, and Gentleneſs. Were you in your Witts? were you ſober? or rather had you not put off common Senſe? Were you not forſaken of your Reaſons, and Underſtandings, that your Wiſdoms could find no better <hi>a Stick of Wood</hi> to make a Prop for a tottering State, on a Crutch for a halting Church, than Sir <hi>Timber?</hi> A Piece ſo crooked, ſo rotten and warped in Principle, Conſcience and Intereſt, that whatever Uſe others may make of him, we poor Farmers cannot judge him fit to make an Hovel-poſt! The Devil was formerly ſo modeſt as to be Content with his Chappel, where God had his Church, but ſeeing he has now aſpired to, and taken Poſſeſſion of the <hi>Temple,</hi> into what Chappel of Eaſe will you crowd th' Almighty?</p>
                  <p>There are few Sinners ſo diſperate, but will ſeek or find ſome Excuſes which they may <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>itch together to palliate their Guilt, and hide their Nakedneſs. But You are certainly forſaken of all Pretences which may mitigate your Crimes, and alleviate your Puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. Can you plead Ignorance, or pretend Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prize when your Sir <hi>Timber</hi> was the <hi>Original Sinner</hi> in the Muſter-roll of the <hi>Club of <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nanimous Voters?</hi> Has he not there ſtood like <hi>Judas</hi> in the Fore-front of the Infernal Regiment of Penſioners? Has not <hi>Common Fame</hi> pinn'd a Paper to his B<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>eaſt, wherein is ſignified to the World how he has ſold his Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try to the Court; Liberty, to Prerogative; and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perty, to Will and Pleaſure? Is he not now notori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly known to the Engliſh World, by the Name of Sir <hi>Timber?</hi> and if you ask him, <hi>who gave him that Name?</hi> muſt he not anſwer, <hi>That either your ſelves, or</hi> Legion, <hi>was his Godfather?</hi> For, did he not once make you a bribeing Preſent of <hi>Timber</hi> to rebuild your Town-houſe; which vaniſht all away by the Magick Art of the ſame Devil that brought it? was he ſo great a Knave to cheat you once, and are not you greater Fools to be cheated twice?</p>
                  <p>But we your plain and honeſt Neighbours do yet hope and pray that you and we may find the Repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſentative Body of <hi>England</hi> of ſo ſound and healthful a Conſtitution, as by the Strength of Nature to purge off thoſe evil Humours which by your Faule they have contracted; and as our late renewed Parliament once before caſt him into the Draught, ſo they will never again lick up their Excrements. And as he was once cut off from their Body as a rotten Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber,
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:96794:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
ſo they will never accept from you a wooden Leg made of ſuch putrified Timber.</p>
                  <p>Yet, had you ſelected out of all thoſe worthy Gentlemen, wherewith your Neighbourhood has plentifully furniſht you, ſome one whoſe Vertues might have corrected the Malignity of his Vices, whoſe Fidelity might have ſeaſon'd his Treachery, and whoſe true Engliſh Spirit might have ballanced his degenerated Spirit; we had ſhewed our Impar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiality in commending what was Good, as well as condemning what was Evil and Unworthy in you, and that we durſt no more conceal your Merits than your Guiltineſs. But you took ſpecial Care, it ſeems, that we ſhould find nothing in you Praiſe-worthy, and have therefore coupled with him a Colleague on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly meet for you and him. Vile Miſcreants! could you find none to be Judge of a trayterous Father, but a treacherous Son? Could you think him meet to ſit within the Walls of the Houſes of Commons, whoſe great Intereſt and Merits lye within the Walls of the Tower? Will not he in his own De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence obſtruct Juſtice, when Juſtice would obſtruct his Poſſeſſion of a vaſt Eſtate amaſſed by betraying us to Arbitrary Power, ſelling us to the <hi>French,</hi> en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſlaving us with a ſtanding Army, which no Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentary Votes, and Acts can disband; and aſſiſting the Papiſts in carrying on their late Plot, and dam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable Treaſons?</p>
                  <p>Had you ſeriouſly reflected upon your Treacherous Actions, had you teſtified your Repentance, or given us any Hopes that you had ſlept out your De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bauch, we had looked on you with ſome Commiſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration; or had your Prieſts called you to the Stool of Repentance, where you had given Satisfaction to the World by Confeſſion of, and Contrition for your Villanies, we had encouraged in our ſelves any feeble Hopes, and in you, any weak Appearan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of Amendment: but when you, and your <hi>Tribe of Levi,</hi> Brethren in Iniquity, maintain a curſed Combination to advance abſolute Power to the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction of our Properties, and to tear from us our Secular, and Civil, as you have already done our Religious Birthrights, and yet no Sign of your returning to a better Mind appears; what could we do leſs than in this innocent and gentle Way chaſtiſe you, till our noble Repreſentatives ſhall convene, in ſome Meaſure to render unto you proportionable to your Works?</p>
                  <p>We do therefore hereby declare our Deteſtation of your Perfidiouſneſs; we proteſt againſt your Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction; we proclaim you Infamous to all after Ages; we renounce all Commerce and Converſe with you as men; we excommunicate you from the Society of all true hearted Engliſhmen; as Chriſtians we will neither Eat nor Drink, Buy nor Sell, Deal nor Trade with you in your Fairs, or Markets. We will ſet the Red-croſs upon your Doors; and do by theſe Preſents warne the whole Kingdom in general, and this Scandaliz'd County in Particular, that they fly, as from a Common Peſtilence, the mortal Contagion of your Perſons, and Habita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions.</p>
                  <p>We ſhall further humbly Petition his Grace, whoſe noble Family has borrow'd a Flower from your now Apoſtatiz'd Corporation, to adorn his Coronet; that he would be pleaſed to procure, and ſue out an Alteration of his Patent, that there may be no noble Family to ſtain it's Coat with ſuch an accurſed Denomination: And ſhall further humbly petition his Sacred Majeſty, that you may be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>franchiſed; a perpetual Brand of Infancy ſet upon you; and never more entruſſed with that Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lege which you have ſo wretchedly abuſed: that ſo the higheſt Officer in your degraded Town may be the <hi>Hog-heard,</hi> ſince you have ſold your Country (like the <hi>Gadarens)</hi> for your ſwiniſh Luſts, and would have ſold your Saviour at the ſame Rate, if any had cheapned him; and your Religion too, ſuch as it is, had any Chapman thought it worth the Buying.</p>
                  <p>And now ye Renegadoes from the Intereſt of your Native Country<hi>!</hi> can you flatter your ſelves that we will ever Reverence your Fox-furre? adore your Thred-bare Gowns? tremble at the Idle Cere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony of your Maſs, or worſhip your titular Gravi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties; who have proſtituted Authority, debauched Power, and now ſtand convicted of a moſt abomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable Conſpiracy againſt the Lives, Liberties, Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion, and Being of <hi>England?</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>If you ſhould chance to Repent (it muſt be againſt your Wills if ever you do;) do not imitate the hypocritical Repen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance of <hi>Ludgerſall,</hi> whoſe dry Drunkenneſs has proved more Pernicious to the Publick Safety, than their Liquid: and have made a worſe Choice, Sober, than perhaps they had ever done when ſtark Mad; and are now the onely Burrough who being Reformed, have contributed to a Nations Ruin.</p>
                  <p>Good Mr. Bailiff! Let not your Worſhips thick skin be too ſenſible that we thus Tan your Hide; and you the Burgeſſes, be patient whilſt we tell you your own, in our Home-ſpun, ruſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſer Language; We do but ſpeak what the whole Nation thinks, and 'tis but ſhort, yet ſweet: you are a pack of Villains, for whom the Gallows hath long groan'd; and that fatal Tree at your Towns-end muſt be for ever barren, till you become its fruit; your Rottenneſs has made you ripe for Hanging; and how would it compleat and crown the Plenty of this Year, could we ſee you, and all our Penſioners hang like ropes of Onyons upon ſuch fruitful Trees. We ſhall confeſs you have made a Choice to ſome Purpoſe, when you have hew'd out a ſubſtantial pair of Gallows out of your own <hi>Timber,</hi> and you and your Brethren ſhall be pleas'd to take a Swing or two under its Shades.</p>
                  <p>You will ſay, perhaps, that we do but rail; and we do inge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuouſly confeſs, there was no help for it<hi>:</hi> the worſt Language we could o'th' ſudden invent, was too good for you<hi>:</hi> we have not the Art to embalm a ſtinking Carrion; we cannot perfume a Dunghill; onely we do heartily repent, that at the beginning of our Addreſs, we Style you <hi>Right Worſhipful,</hi> and <hi>Worſhipful;</hi> forgive us this one time of treating you unſuitable to your Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits; and we do religiouſly promiſe that for the future we will Blazon you in your proper Colours, and deſcribe you by your particular Titles; which you muſt be content ſhould be none of the beſt, ſince you have taken ſuch care to deſerve no better.</p>
                  <p>In the mean time, we had left you to be chaſtis'd by the Stings and Laſhes of your own Conſciences; but they being long ſince mortified and paſt feeling, we muſt reſign you to the Divine Vengeance, to be made in due time by ſome ſignal Judgments a Publick Example to the World, and a fair Warn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to all that ſhall hereafter dare to betray their God, their King, and their Countrey.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <salute>Moſt <hi>Hang-worthy</hi> Gentlemen! Go recreate your ſelves upon a Gallows made of your own <hi>TIMBER TEMPLE.</hi>
                     </salute> So pray moſt devoutly <signed>your daily Orators, The honeſt poor Farmers of the Neighbouring Villages, <hi>S. T: R. W.</hi> &amp;c.</signed>
                  </closer>
                  <postscript>
                     <head>POSTSCRIPT.</head>
                     <opener>
                        <salute>Mr. Bailiff!</salute>
                     </opener>
                     <p>WE have ſent you encloſed the <hi>New Buckingham Ballad,</hi> which you may do well to cauſe to be read in your Town-Hall. Sir <hi>Timber Temple</hi> preſents his humble Service to your Lady; (ſhe knows the meaning of it) and ſo would We to the <hi>Ni<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ty Barber</hi> your Brother, but that we owe him none, and have little enough to pay where it is due.</p>
                  </postscript>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <body>
               <div type="instructions">
                  <pb facs="tcp:96794:3"/>
                  <pb n="107" facs="tcp:96794:3"/>
                  <head>THE OFFICE OF THE Overſeers of the Poor.</head>
                  <div n="1" type="chapter">
                     <head>CHAP. I. <hi>Of the Antiquity of theſe Officers, of their Quali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fications, and how, and when to be choſen.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THoſe to be choſen to this Office, ought to be ſubſtantial Perſons, Men of Wiſdom and a good Conſcience; they mull be Houſholders, for this Name and Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice may beſeem the Beſt, and not the meaneſt Men, (it being an Office of great Antiquity and Excellency;) For as God himſelf hath a ſpecial Reſpect to the Miſeries of the Poor, ſo they be like God that provide for the Neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitles of the Poor, <hi>Dalt. J. P.</hi> 143.</p>
                     <p>The Overſeers of the Poor are to be choſen yearly, and joyned with the Churchwardens of the Pariſh in the overſight and ordering of the Poor of the Pariſh. They are to be choſen by two or more Juſtices of the Peace, ſone whereof to be of the <hi>Quorum)</hi> who are
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:96794:4"/>
yearly under their Hands and Seals at Eaſter, or within one Month after, to appoint four, three, or two ſubſtantial Houſholders, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the greatneſs of the Pariſh, to be joyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed with the Churchwardens to look to the Poor of the Pariſh, Stat. 43 <hi>Eliz. c.</hi> 2. 21 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 28.</p>
                     <p>The major part of theſe Officers, without the reſt of them, may do any thing belonging to their Office. But they are to have the allowance and conſent either in particular, or in general, of two Juſtices of the Peace <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> to every thing they do about their Office. And theſe Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers, or ſuch of them as ſhall not be let by juſt excuſe (to be allowed by two Juſtices) are to meet monthly in the Church on Sunday after Evening Prayer, and there are to conſider of ſome meet directions about their Office, and they are to uſe all poſſible diligence in their Office on pain to forfeit for every ſuch Default twenty ſhillings, 43. <hi>El. c.</hi> 3. <hi>Wingates Stat. Tit. Poor People.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>And if it happen that Overſeers be not ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed according to the 43 <hi>El.</hi> then every Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice of Peace or Head Officer of that Diviſion or Corporation ſhall forfeit 5. <hi>l.</hi> to be levied by a Seſſions Warrant, and imployed to the uſe of the Poor of the Pariſhes where ſuch de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault is made, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>3 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2. <hi>Wingates Stat. Tit. Poor People.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="2" type="chapter">
                     <pb n="109" facs="tcp:96794:4"/>
                     <head>CHAP. II. <hi>Of the ſeveral ſorts of Poor People, and what Poor the Overſeers are to provide for, and relieve, or to ſet to work.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THere are three ſorts or degrees of Poor, as firſt, the Poor by Impotency and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect, as the Aged and Decrepit that are paſt their Labour; the Infant, Fatherleſs and Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therleſs, and not able to work; the Perſon natu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally diſabled either in Wit or Member, as an Ideot, Lunatick, Blind, Lame, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> not being able to work; and the Perſon viſited with grievous Sickneſs or Diſeaſe, though caſually, yet thereby for the time being impotent. All theſe the O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſeers are to provide for, that they have ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary Relief, and Allowances proportionable, and according to the continuance and meaſure of their Maladies and Needs, and of theſe it may be ſaid, <hi>Si non paviſti, occidiſti, Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</hi> 169.</p>
                     <p>Then ſecondly, The Poor by Caſualty, as a Perſon caſually diſabled or maimed in his Body, as the Soldier or Labourer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> maimed in their lawful Callings the Houſholder decayed by caſualty of Fire, Water, Robbery, Suretiſhip, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and the poor Man over charged with Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren: All theſe (and ſuch like others) having Ability, and ſtrength of Body, but not ſufficient Means to maintain themſelves, are to be ſet to work by the Overſeers, and being not able to live by their Work, they are in Charity to be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieved in ſome reaſonable proportion, according
<pb n="110" facs="tcp:96794:5"/>
to their ſeveral Wants and Neceſſities, <hi>Da<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap> J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> ibid.</p>
                     <p>Then laſtly, The thriftleſs Poor, as the r<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tous and prodigal Perſon, that conſumes all w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Play or Drinking, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the diſſolute Perſon, as t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Strumpet, Pilferer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the ſlothful Perſon th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> refuſeth to work, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and the Vagabond the will abide in no place or ſervice; and for all the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> the Houſe of Correction is the place where the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> are to be ſent to, and being of able Bodies, then they are to be held to hard Labour, and to main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain themſelves by their Labour and Work, w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap> out charging the Town or County for any Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowance, 7 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 4 <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>ſol.</hi> 170.</p>
                     <p>But it ſeemeth, that if any of theſe laſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ort<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Poor happen to prove impotent, and alſo <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> caſes of manifeſt extremity, then they are to b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> relieved by the Town, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> ibid<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </p>
                     <p>If the Parents be able to work and may har<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Work, they are to find their Children by thee labour, and not the Pariſh; but if they be over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged with Children, they may help, by having ſome of their Children put out Apprenticeth by the Overſeers, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 157.</p>
                     <p>The Father, Grandfather, Mother, Grand-mother, and the Children and Grandchildren of every poor impotent Perſon not able <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> work, being of ſufficient Ability, ſhall relieve ſuc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> poor Perſons in ſuch manner, as the Juſtices <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Peace of that County (where ſuch ſufficient Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon dwelleth) at their General Quarter Seſſion ſhall Aſſeſs; and if ſuch Perſon refuſe to ab<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap> the Order, they forfeit 20 <hi>s.</hi> for every mond to the Poor of the Pariſh, which forfeiture 1. to he levied by the Church wardens or Overſeen or one of them, by Warrant from any two ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices
<pb n="111" facs="tcp:96794:5"/>
of the Peace <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> within their Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mits, by diſtreſs and ſale of the Offenders Goods, and want of diſtreſs, any two ſuch Juſtices may commit the Offender to priſon, there to remain without Bail till the ſaid Forfeiture be paid, 43 <hi>El.</hi> 2. <hi>Reſol. Judges</hi> 16, 17. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 156.</p>
                     <p>But if a Man marry a Grandmother that hath no Eſtate, the Grandfather in Law is not chargeable: But if ſhe hath an Eſtate cauſed without ſuch Marriage, or that comes after Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage by deſcent, or otherwiſe to her, here he may be charged: But where they have raiſed themſelves an Eſtate by their own Induſtry, there it is doubtful. But in no caſe ſhall he be charged longer than his Wife lives; and it ſeems alſo Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtard Children are not within this Law, neither can the Juſtices do any thing therein againſt a Man that lives out of their County. See <hi>Boulſt. Rep.</hi> 2 <hi>part, f.</hi> 245, 246, 247.</p>
                     <p>No Poor may beg but in their own Pariſh, and there by Licence of the Overſeers of the Poor; and they may not licence them to beg in the High-ways there, and without the Licence of the Overſeers they may not beg at all, <hi>Reſ. Judges</hi> 15. <hi>Dalt. J. P. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 157. 39 <hi>El.</hi> 3.</p>
                     <p>No Inhabitants may ſerve any Poor at their Door, but thoſe of their own Pariſh, that have licence from the Overſeers of the Poor to beg there, under pain of 10. <hi>s</hi> for every time they do ſo, 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 7. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 83. <hi>f.</hi> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>20.</p>
                     <p>Theſe Officers are to make proviſion for a poor Man that wants an Houſe (but not for a common Herdſman or Sheperd) with conſent of the Lord of the Mannor firſt had in writing under his Hand and Seal, either by themſelves, or with
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:96794:6"/>
a Seſſions Order, may erect a Cottage upon any part of the Waſte of a Mannor, and lodge In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mates therein, notwithſtanding the Stat. 31 <hi>El.</hi> 7. But ſuch Cottage may not be afterwards employ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed otherwiſe than to lodge impotent Perſons there, for if it be, then it falls within the penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the 31 <hi>El.</hi> aforeſaid, 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2 <hi>Wingates. Stat. Tit. Poor People.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>All ſuch Perſons married or unmarried, having no Means to maintain them, uſing no ordinary and daily Trade of Life to get their Living by, and ſuch Perſons alſo as can get no Work, are to be ſet on Work by the Overſeers; and any one Juſtice of Peace may ſend to the Houſe of Corre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, or Common Goal, ſuch as ſhall not imploy themſelves to work being appointed thereto by the Churchwardens and Overſeers of the Poor of the Pariſh, 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 143.</p>
                     <p>And to this purpoſe the Churchwardens and Overſeers of the Poor may, by, and with the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent of two or more Juſtices of the Peace <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> &amp;c. Set up uſe, and occupy any Trade, My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery or Occupation, only for the ſetting on Work, and better Relief of the Poor of the Pariſh, Town or Place where they are Overſeers, &amp;c. 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. <hi>c.</hi> 4. <hi>Dalt. J<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 148. <hi>Wingates Stat. Tit. Poor People.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="3" type="chapter">
                     <pb n="113" facs="tcp:96794:6"/>
                     <head>CHAP. III. <hi>The Duty of the Overſeers about putting forth, and binding of Apprentices, with the Form of the Indenture for that purpoſe.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>IN the putting out of Children Apprentices, there ought to be regard had to the Maſter, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he Child, and the Parents; Firſt, to the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, that he be of Ability and Honeſty, otherwiſe by ſome device or hard intreaty they may pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voke their Apprentices to depart or run away; and regard is alſo to be had to his Trade or Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culty, leſt the Apprentice conſume his time without learning any thing: Secondly, Regard is to be had to the Apprentices to put them out timely, and while they are young and tract<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able (ſo that they be above the Age of ſeven years) otherwiſe by reaſon of their idle and baſe Educations, they will hardly keep their Service, or imploy themſelves to work: Then laſtly, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gard is to be had to the Parents, to take a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way ſuch from them as are brought up to live <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>dly and looſly, or elſe ſuch as are a burthen and charge to their Parents, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 150, 151.</p>
                     <p>The choice of theſe Apprentices, are to be out of the pooreſt ſort of Children, whoſe Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rents are the leaſt able to relieve them, and they are to be above 7, and under 15 years of Age, when they are firſt bound, 7 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 3. <hi>Wingates Stat. Tit. Poor People.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>And theſe Officers are to have the conſent of two Juſtices of the Peace in the placing out of ſuch Apprentices; and they may bind the Man-child
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:96794:7"/>
till 24 years of Age, and the Woman chi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> till 21 years of Age, or till ſhe be married, wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> ſhall firſt happen: And theſe Apprentices m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> be bound to Weavers, Maſons, Dyers, Fullen, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> any other Trade, as well as to Husbandry <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Houſewifery, See 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 14<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>Wingates Stat. Tit. Poor People.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Now this placing of Apprentices may be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> any Man, whom the Officers and Juſtices think<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> to receive them, within the ſame Pariſh, or elſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where in other Pariſhes within the ſame H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dred, either with, or without Mony; therefo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> it is fit in this caſe to conſider, if the Child <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> young, and the Party to whom they place it i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> not very able, then they may give Mony, if the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> pleaſe, as the Party and they ſhall agree, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>Judges</hi> 1633. <hi>Queſt.</hi> 1.</p>
                     <p>All Men that-have; or may have uſe for Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants, as Knights, Clergy-men, Gentlemen, a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Yeomen, as well as Tradeſmen, are bound to ta<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Apprentices; yea, though wealthy Men Tab<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> themſelves, or live ſo privately, that they haven<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> uſe for a Servant, yet they may be compelled <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> take them, or elſe to pay a Sum of Mony for put<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting them Apprentices elſewhere; and if they refuſe to pay the Sum impoſed upon them, tw<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Juſtices of the Peace may make their Warra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> to levy the ſame by diſtreſs and ſale of the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders Goods, <hi>Reſ. Judges</hi> 1633. <hi>Quest.</hi> 4. <hi>Po<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                              <desc>•••</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> 24. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 151.</p>
                     <p>Or the Refuſers to take Apprentices, may be preſented and indicted for the ſame, upon the <hi>Stat.</hi> 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2. at the Aſſizes or Seſſions of the Peace, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> ibid. <hi>Reſ. Judges</hi> 1633 <hi>Queſt.</hi> 7.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="115" facs="tcp:96794:7"/>
An Apprentice put to a Man in reſpect of his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>arm, when his Leaſe expireth, the Apprentice <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hall go ſtill with the Farm, if the firſt Maſter be ſo pleaſed; otherwiſe it is where an Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentice is put to a Man in regard of his Abili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, or for other Reſpects. And where any dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferences are between the Officers and the Man that is to receive an Apprentice, about Mony, and what Mony ſhall be given or otherwiſe, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>here the Juſtices thereabouts, or in their De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faults, the Seſſions muſt end it, <hi>Reſ. Judges</hi> 1633. <hi>Queſt.</hi> 2. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 151.</p>
                     <p>If the Parents of poor Children ſhall refuſe to let their Children be put forth Apprentices (without good cauſe ſhewed) ſuch Parents may be bound over, by the Juſtices, to anſwer their ſaid Default, and if the Children ſhall refuſe, the Juſtices may ſend them to the Houſe of Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection, there to remain till they be content to be bound and ſerve, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>&amp;</hi> 58. <hi>f.</hi> 153. <hi>&amp;</hi> 119.</p>
                     <p>Note, That this binding muſt be by Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, and may not well be done by a verbal A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greement; and the Indenture muſt be either between the Juſtices, Churchwardens and Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeers, or them and the Apprentice on the one part, and him that takes the Apprentice of the other part, as appears by the Form of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture in the end of this Chapter; and he muſt be named by the Name of Apprentice ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſly, or elſe he is no Apprentice, though he be bound, <hi>Cromp.</hi> 184. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 5. <hi>f.</hi> 120.</p>
                     <p>And this binding is as effectual to all pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſes, as if the Children were of full Age, and did bind themſelves by Indentures and Covenants; and all ſuch as are bound by the Overſeers, as
<pb n="116" facs="tcp:96794:8"/>
aboveſaid, may ſafely be received and kept <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Apprentices by their Maſters, 1 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 25. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 28. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 58. <hi>fol.</hi> 120. 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. <hi>c.</hi> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 5 <hi>El. c.</hi> 4. <hi>Cromp.</hi> 184. <hi>b.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Such Mony as is given to put out poor C<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dren Apprentices, is to be employed in Corpo<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rate Towns, by the Corporations, and in othe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> plac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>s by the Parſon or Vicar, together with th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Conſtables Churchwardens, and Overſeers of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Poor, or the moſt part of them; who ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap> forbear to refuſe to employ the ſame accord<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ingly, on pain to forfeit five marks, each o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> them ſo making default, to be divided betwi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> the Poor of the Pariſh and the Proſecutor, 7 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 3. <hi>Wingates Stat. Tit. Poor People.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>The Party taking any Mony with ſu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>h Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentice, ſhall give good Security by Obligatio<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> to repay it at the end of ſeven years next en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuing the date of the ſaid Obligation, or withi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> the three months after the end of the ſaid ſeve<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> years; and if ſuch Apprentice ſhall die withi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> ſeven years, then within one year after his or her death; and if the Maſter, Miſtreſs or Dame hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen to die within the ſeven years, then withi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> one year after their death; ſo as the Mony may be employed in placing the Apprentice with ſome other of the ſame Trade, to ſerve out his time, at the diſcretion of the Parties truſted as aforeſaid, 7 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 3.</p>
                     <p>And the Mony ſo given ſhall be imployed within three months after the Receipt thereof, and if there ſhall not be apt Perſons found in the places where it is given to the Apprentices, it ſhall then be imployed in the Pariſhes next adjoyning, by the Parties that are truſted with it, in the place where it was ſo given, and
<pb n="117" facs="tcp:96794:8"/>
there alſo Bond ſhall be taken, as afore is decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ed, 7 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 3.</p>
                     <p>If the Maſter ſhall put his Apprentice into Apparel, it is a Gift in Law, and he cannot <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>fterwards take it away, though he ſhould part <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ith his Apprentice, <hi>Br. Tranſgr.</hi> 93.</p>
                     <p>An Apprentice cannot be diſcharged from his Apprenticeſhip but by four Juſtices of the Peace <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>t the leaſt, and in open Seſſions, or elſe by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he Agreement of the Maſter and Apprentice, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>nd under his Maſters Hand in Writing, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 58. <hi>f.</hi> 121.</p>
                     <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="form_of_indenture">
                        <body>
                           <head>The Form of theſe Indentures, mentioned before, is as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi>
                           </head>
                           <p>
                              <hi>THIS Indenture made the 29th day of</hi> Sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tember, <hi>in the 20th Year of the Reign of Our moſt Gracious Sovereign Lord</hi> Charles <hi>the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                                 <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap>nd, by the Grace of God of</hi> England, Scotland, France <hi>and</hi> Ireland, <hi>King, Defender of the Faith, &amp;c.</hi> Anno<expan>
                                 <am>
                                    <g ref="char:abque"/>
                                 </am>
                                 <ex>que</ex>
                              </expan> Dom. 1668. <hi>witneſſeth, that</hi> J. W. <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap>nd</hi> G. R. <hi>Overſeers of the Poor in the Town of</hi> Kirk-Leaventon, <hi>and</hi> J. R. <hi>Churchwardens of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap>me Town, by and with the conſent of Sir</hi> J. P. <hi>Knight and Baronet, and</hi> T. M. <abbr>Esq</abbr> 
                              <hi>two of his Majeſties Juſtices of Peace for the North Riding <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap>f the County of</hi> York, <hi>have by theſe Preſents <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap>laced and bound</hi> J. T. <hi>(being a poor fatherleſs child) as an Apprentice with</hi> E. H. <hi>of</hi> Kirk-Lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venton <hi>aforeſaid, Widow; and as an Apprentice with her the ſaid</hi> E. H. <hi>to dwell from the day of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap>ate of theſe Preſents, until ſhe the ſaid</hi> J. T. <hi>ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap>ome to the Age of</hi> 21 <hi>years, or be married, which <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap>hall firſt happen, according to the Statute in that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap>aſe made and provided, by and during all which</hi>
                              <pb n="118" facs="tcp:96794:9"/>
                              <hi>time and term the ſaid</hi> J. T. <hi>ſhall the ſaid</hi> E. H. <hi>her Dame well and faithfully ſerve in all <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                                    <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                                 </gap> lawful Buſineſs as the ſaid</hi> E. H. <hi>ſhall put <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap> the ſaid</hi> J. T. <hi>unto, according to her Power, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap> and Ability, and honeſtly and obediently in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap> things ſhall behave her ſelf toward her ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                                    <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                                 </gap> and Children, and all the reſt of the Family <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap> the ſaid</hi> E. H. <hi>And the ſaid</hi> E. H. <hi>for h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap>r <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                                    <desc>•••</desc>
                                 </gap> promiſeth, covenanteth, and agreeth that ſhe t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap> ſaid</hi> E. H. <hi>the aforeſaid</hi> J. T. <hi>in the Art and Sk<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap> of Houſewifry, the beſt manner that ſhe can, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap> may, ſhall teach and inform, or cauſe to be taug<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap> and informed, as much as thereunto belongeth, a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap> ſhe the ſaid</hi> E. H. <hi>knoweth; and alſo during <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap> the ſaid Term, to find unto her ſaid Apprentice, Meat, Drink, Linnen, Woollen, Hoſe, Shooes, W<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap>
                                 <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and all other things needful or meet for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                                    <desc>••</desc>
                                 </gap> Apprentice. In Witneſs whereof,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
                        </body>
                     </floatingText>
                     <p>Note, If it be a Boy that is to be bound Ap<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>prentice to Husbandry, or any other Trade, th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> he may be bound till 24 years of Age, as <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> ſhew'd before in this Chapter.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="4" type="chapter">
                     <head>CHAP. IV. <hi>Several Caſes about Settlements, and alſo touching Baſtards,</hi> &amp;c.</head>
                     <p>TOuching ſettling of poor People, the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices are to meddle with none but thoſe who are impotent, and ſuch as are like to be chargeable to the place where they are <hi>Boulſt. Rep.</hi> 1 <hi>part,</hi> 347.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="119" facs="tcp:96794:9"/>
By 13 <hi>&amp;</hi> 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>cap.</hi> 12. It is Enacted, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hat upon complaint by the Churchwardens, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>d Overſeers of the Poor, to any Juſtice of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>eace within forty days after any poor Perſon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ometh to ſettle in a Tenement under 10 <hi>l. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>r annum,</hi> two Juſtices of Peace, whereof one <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>o be of the <hi>Quorum,</hi> may by Warrant remove <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>ch Perſon to the Pariſh where they were laſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>gally ſettled for forty days, unleſs they give <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>curity to be allowed by the ſaid Juſtices for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>iſcharge of the Pariſh: Perſons aggrieved may <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ppeal to the Quarter Seſſions.</p>
                     <p>But Perſons having a Certificate from the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>iniſter of the Pariſh, and one Churchwarden, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>nd one Overſeer of the Poor, declaring them <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>habitants there, may go into any Pariſh to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ork, and the not returning of ſuch Perſons, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hen their Work is finiſhed, or falling Sick <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hilſt they are at Work, ſhall not be accounted Settlement: If any return to the Pariſh from <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hence they are removed, a Juſtice of Peace <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ay ſend them to the Houſe of Correction, to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>e puniſhed as Vagabonds, or to a publick <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ork houſe to be imployed in Labour: and if <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he Churchwardens and Overſeers of any Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>ſh to which any are removed, refuſe to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>eive them, and provide them Work, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>uſtice of Peace may bind over ſuch Officers to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he Aſſizes or Seſſions.</p>
                     <p>Churchwardens and Overſeers for the Poor <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>here any Baſtard-Child ſhall be born, may <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> ſo much of the Goods and Profits of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ands of the Putative Father and Lewd Mother, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> two Juſtices of Peace ſhall order towards <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>iſcharge of the Pariſh, to be confirmed at the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>eſſions: who may make an Order for the
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:96794:10"/>
Churchwardens, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to diſpoſe of the Goo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> by ſale or otherwiſe as they ſhall think <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> and receive the Profits of ſo much of the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Lands, as ſhall be ordered by the Seſſions.</p>
                     <p>The Poor in every Town-ſhip or Village <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>Lancaſhire, Cheſhire, Darbyſhire, Yorkſhire, N<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                           <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>thumberland, Biſhoprick of Durham, Cumberla<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> and <hi>Weſtmoreland</hi> ſhall be provided for in t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Townſhip and Village where they inhabit, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> were laſt legally ſettled: And two or more O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſeers ſhall be choſen in every Townſhip <hi>&amp;c.</hi> who ſhall execute all powers for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lief of the Poor under the Penalties mentioned in 43 <hi>Eliz. c.</hi> 2.</p>
                     <p>This Act of 13 <hi>&amp;</hi> 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 12. was <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> continue no longer than to the end of the firſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Seſſion of the next Parliament, but revived by 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 17. to continue for ſeven years, and to the end of the firſt Seſſion of the next Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament.</p>
                     <p>And whereas poor Perſons at their fir<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> coming to a Pariſh, do commonly conceal them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, the forty days intended by the ſaid Act to make Settlement, ſhall be accounted fro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> the time of their deliveries of notice in writ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of their Houſe of Abode, and the number of their Family, if they have any, to one of the Churchwardens or Overſeers of the Poor of the ſaid Pariſh, 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 17.</p>
                     <p>No Man but a Vagraut Begger, ought to b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> ſent out of any Pariſh to the place of his Birth or laſt Habitation; for if any refuſe to work in the Pariſh where he is ſettled, or to work for the Wages aſſeſſed, then he is by the Juſtices to be ſent to the Houſe of Correction, <hi>Co.</hi> 2
<pb n="121" facs="tcp:96794:10"/>
                        <hi>part Inſt. fol.</hi> 730. 7 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 4. <hi>Reſol. Judges</hi> 9. <hi>Dalt. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 157. 39 <hi>El. c.</hi> 4. 1 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 7.</p>
                     <p>If a Scholar in the Univerſity, or in a Gram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ar School begin to be ſuſpect, he may be, or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> he doth become impotent, and is like to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>e a Charge to the Pariſh where he is, he muſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>e ſent to his Parents if he have any, other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>iſe to the place where he was laſt legally <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>ttled before he came to School, <hi>Reſ. Judges</hi> 633. <hi>ſect.</hi> 32.</p>
                     <p>If one be Born, and live 20 years in <hi>A.</hi> and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hen go to <hi>B.</hi> and there live in a Houſe and pay <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>is Rent, and after he come to <hi>C.</hi> and there <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>orks 20 Weeks as a Labourer in a Quarry of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ones, where he breaks his Back, and becomes <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>potent, and there is taken vagrant and beg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>ng, in this caſe he muſt be ſent to <hi>A.</hi> the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>lace of his Birth, and there muſt be provided <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>r, <hi>Reſ. Judges,</hi> 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 1.</p>
                     <p>If a Man that hath a Wife and Children, take <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Houſe in one Pariſh for a Year, and during <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>is time he is illegally forced out of his Poſſeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>on; then he takes an Houſe as Inmate in ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Pariſh, out of which he is put within two <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> three days, and then not having any place <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> be in, he gets into a Barn in the third place, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>d there his Wife is delivered of another <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hild: In this caſe they are all to be ſent to the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ariſh out of which they were firſt illegally <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>rced, <hi>Reſol. Judges</hi> 1633. <hi>ſect.</hi> 24.</p>
                     <p>One Born in <hi>D.</hi> left that place for the ſpace <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> 20 years, then lived in <hi>S.</hi> took an Houſe and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>id Rent, and left that place alſo ſix or ſeven <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ears, and then came to <hi>L.</hi> in another County, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>nd there was twenty Weeks, did Work, and
<pb n="122" facs="tcp:96794:11"/>
there became impotent, and did wander, a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> beg in the ſame place, and was taken as a Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grant, and it was ordered he ſhould be paſſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> and ſettled at <hi>D.</hi> where he was Born, by t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Judges at <hi>Worceſter</hi> Aſſizes, 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. <hi>Boulſt. R<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> 1 <hi>part, f.</hi> 375.</p>
                     <p>No Child under the Age of ſeven years ſh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> be adjudged a Rogue within the <hi>Stat.</hi> 39 <hi>El. c.</hi> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> But it ſeems ſuch Children vagrant and begging muſt be ſent and placed with the Father <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Husband of the Wife; and if he be dead, the with the Mother (where ſhe was born, or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> dwelt by the ſpace of one year) and ſuch Chi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dren, once thus ſettled or placed, muſt the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>e remain, and not be ſent from thence to the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> place of Birth, though after their Parents die<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> or run away, or that the ſaid Children gr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> above the Age of ſeven years, yea, though th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> ſaid Children after beg, and prove vagrant <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> the Town, for there they muſt be ſet to labo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> by the Overſeers of the Poor, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 8<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. <hi>f.</hi> 209.</p>
                     <p>But Children above ſeven years of Age, go<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing about vagrant, or begging in the Cou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>try, ſhall be puniſhed as Rogues, and ſent <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> their place of Birth, <hi>Dalt. J. P. ch.</hi> 83. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> 209.</p>
                     <p>The Wife being a Vagrant Rogue, muſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> ſent to her Husband, though he be but a Ser<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>vant in another Town; and where the Husband and Wife have an Houſe, (though as an I<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate) and either of them Rogue about, i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> this caſe they are to be ſent to the place wher<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> the Houſe is, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 83. <hi>fol.</hi> 209.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="123" facs="tcp:96794:11"/>
The Rogue, whoſe place of birth or laſt dwelling cannot be known, having Wife and Children under ſeven years of Age, they muſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>o with the Husband to the place where they <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>vere laſt wilfully ſuffered to paſs through with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out puniſhment, where the Children muſt be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>elleved by the Work of their Parents, though <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he Parents be committed to the Houſe of Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ection; and if the Rogue have Children above <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>even years of Age, that Rogue about with him, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hen they are to be ſent to the Houſe of Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection alſo with the Parents, and when they come out again, then to their ſeveral places of births, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 83. <hi>f.</hi> 206. and <hi>Shephards Guide</hi> for <hi>J. P. pag.</hi> 252. <hi>Reſ.</hi> &amp;c. <hi>b.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>If I live in a Houſe in <hi>A.</hi> there with my Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren, but I work in <hi>B.</hi> where I am hired by the year, in this caſe my Children ſhall be in <hi>A.</hi> but <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>f I have an Houſe in <hi>B.</hi> they ſhall be placed there, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 158.</p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>A.</hi> being a Wanderer with three Children born in three Pariſhes, comes to <hi>Dale</hi> with them to her Siſter, and there dieth ſhortly after, here the Children muſt be ſettled in the ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Pariſhes where they were born, and not in the Pariſh where the Mother died, <hi>Boulſt. Rep.</hi> 2 <hi>part,</hi> 351.</p>
                     <p>No Man is to be put out of the Town where he dwelleth, and is lawfully ſettled, nor to be ſent to his place of Bith, or laſt Habitation, but a Vagrant Rogue, not to be found by the Town, except the Party be imporent, but they ought to ſet themſelves to labour, if they be able and can get Work; and if they cannot get Work, then the Overſeers are to ſet them to work; and if in ſuch caſe ſuch Perſons wander abroad
<pb n="124" facs="tcp:96794:12"/>
begging out of the Pariſh, then they may be ſent as Vagabonds (from the place where they ſhall be taken wandring or begging) to the place of their Birth, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 83. <hi>f.</hi> 209.</p>
                     <p>If a Maid Servant be gotten with Child at <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> by her Fellow-Servant (or by another Man <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> the ſame Town) and after both their Service ended, they Marry, and then the young M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> is retained at <hi>B.</hi> and afterwards the Woman is delivered of her Child, in this caſe ſhe wi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> her Child are to be ſent to the Father at <hi>B.</hi> a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> there muſt be ſettled, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73 <hi>f.</hi> 159.</p>
                     <p>If any diſturbance be made to any Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment lawfully ordered by the Juſtices, either by the Conſtables refuſing to receive and convey a Rogue where they ought to do it, or by the Churchwardens and overſeers of the Poor in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſing ſuch an one as is duly ſent to be ſettle<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> there, in ſuch caſe they forfeit 5 <hi>l.</hi> by the 39 <hi>El. c.</hi> 4.</p>
                     <p>If a Woman unmarried be hired Weekly, Monthly, half Year, or Yearly, in one Pariſh, and there be gotten with Child, and then goeth it to another Pariſh, and there is ſettled in Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, or otherwiſe for two or three Months, and then ſhe is diſcovered to be with Child, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> this caſe ſhe and her Child ſhall be ſettled i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> the Pariſh where ſhe then is, and muſt not be ſent to the Pariſh whence ſhe came, <hi>Reſol. Judg<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> 1633. <hi>ſect.</hi> 12.</p>
                     <p>If a Woman be delivered of a Baſtard Chil<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> in one Pariſh, and then go into another Pari<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> with her Child, in this caſe the Child after it is nurſed, is to be ſent to, and ſettled in the place where it was born, and not to remain with the Mother, <hi>Reſol. Judges</hi> 1633. <hi>ſect.</hi> 23.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="125" facs="tcp:96794:12"/>
If <hi>A.</hi> have a Baſtard Child by <hi>B.</hi> born in <hi>Dale,</hi> and the reputed Father marries ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Woman, and they breed the Child 10 years in the Pariſh of <hi>Salt,</hi> and the Mother of the Child is in Service all this while, and a ſingle Woman, the reputed Father dies; in this caſe the Child is to be ſent to the Mother firſt, to be maintained by her, if ſhe be able, and if not, it muſt be kept by the Pariſh of <hi>Salt,</hi> where it was ſettled with the Father 10 years, <hi>Boulſt. Rep.</hi> 2 <hi>part, fol.</hi> 350.</p>
                     <p>If a Woman have a Baſtard Child, and is like to be chargeable to the Pariſh, and ſhe is ſent to the Houſe of Correction for it (as ſhe may be by Law) in this caſe it hath been queſtion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed whether the Child muſt go with her, or re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main in the Town where it was born, (or ſet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led with the Mother) and there to be relieved by the Work of the Mother, or by Relief from the Reputed Father, upon the 18 <hi>El.</hi> and it ſeems moſt reaſonable to be ſo; and yet the common opinion and practice is otherwiſe, (to wit) to ſend the Child with the Mother to the Houſe of Correction: And this may alſo ſeem reaſonable where the Child ſucketh on the Mother, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 11. <hi>f.</hi> 41.</p>
                     <p>If a Woman with Child be ſent to the Houſe of Correction, and there be delivered; the Child muſt be ſent back to the Pariſh where the Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man came from, there to be relieved. Alſo if a Woman be travelling, and have her Child with her, and is apprehended and ſent to the Goal, and there hanged for Felony, in this caſe the Child ſhall not be chargeable to the place where the Goal is, but to the place where it was born (if it can be known) otherwiſe to
<pb n="126" facs="tcp:96794:13"/>
the place where the Mother was apprehended<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and ſo was the opinion of Sir <hi>Nicholas Hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 1.</p>
                     <p>The two next Juſtices <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> next to the Limits where the Pariſh Church <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> may take order as well for the puniſhment o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> the Mother, and reputed Father of a Baſtar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Child, as alſo for the Relief of the Pariſh whe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> it is born, by charging the Mother and Fathe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> with the payment of Mony weekly toward the keeping of it, or otherwiſe<hi>:</hi> And if the Mother or Father perform not the Juſtices or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der therein, they are to ſuffer Impriſonme<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> without Bail, except he or ſhe give Security <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> perform, or elſe to appear at the next Seſſions, and abide the order of the Juſtices there, if any be made there; and if none be made, then <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> ſtand to the firſt order, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 11. <hi>f.</hi> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 3.</p>
                     <p>Note, That this Order may be made by any two Juſtices of the County <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> as it <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> held by ſome, but moſt properly by the t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> next Juſtices, and the queſtion muſt be abo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> ſuch a Baſtard Child as is like to be a charge to the Pariſh; and the Security muſt be give<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> to the Pariſh where the Child is born, to ſe<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cure the Pariſh from the charge of the Child, or to keep the Child: it muſt be a Pariſh with in the County where the two Juſtices have power, and the Order muſt be certain how long the reputed Father muſt keep the Child, ſecure the Pariſh, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and it muſt be made a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Perſon that is ſuſpected to have got<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten the Baſtard Child, and not againſt anothe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Perſon to contribute towards it, becauſe it was gotten in his Houſe, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and the Order muſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <pb n="127" facs="tcp:96794:13"/>
expreſs the Child by the Name of a Baſtard Child, and not the reputed Child of ſuch an <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>e; and the Juſtices for the better diſcovery of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he Matter, may upon Oath examine the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>her her ſelf concerning the reputed Father, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he time, &amp;c. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 11. <hi>fol.</hi> 40. 18 <hi>Eliz. c.</hi> 3. 7 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 4. See <hi>Steels Rep. fol.</hi> 154, 245, 246, 247, 388. and ſee <hi>Pridgeons</hi> Caſe, <hi>Hill.</hi> 9 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. <hi>B. R.</hi> and <hi>Slaters</hi> Caſe, <hi>Paſch.</hi> 13 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. <hi>B. R. Cro. Rep.</hi> 1 <hi>part.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="5" type="chapter">
                     <head>CHAP. V. <hi>The Overſeers Office in making of Rates, and paſſing Accounts.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THE Churchwardens and Overſeers of the Poor, or the greater part of them (for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he doing and performing of the things they have in charge) may raiſe weekly, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe by Taxation of every Parſon, Vicar, and other Occupier of Land, Houſe or Tithes, Cole<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mines, or ſaleable Underwoods, within the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>iſh, Town, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſuch a Sum as they ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hink fit; and this Rate they muſt have allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and confirmed under the Hands of two Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> and then by Warrant from <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hem, or any other two Juſtices <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hey may levy by diſtreſs and ſale of the Goods of the Party refuſing to pay the ſaid Tax, rendring the overplus to the Owners, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>n default of Diſtreſs, two ſuch Juſtices may commit the Party to priſon, there to remain without Bail till he be diſcharged by him, 43 <hi>El.</hi>
                        <pb n="128" facs="tcp:96794:14"/>
                        <hi>ch.</hi> 2. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 148. <hi>Wingates Stat. Tit<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Poor People.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Now theſe Rates ought to be well and tr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> made, according to Mens viſible Eſtates, real <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> perſonal, within the place only, and not ſo any Eſtate elſewhere; at <hi>Lincoln</hi> Aſſiſes, 9 <hi>Can.</hi> by Juſtice <hi>Hutton</hi> and <hi>Crook.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Note, That a Pariſh in Reputation, ſhall be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Pariſh within this Law<hi>:</hi> ſo that if <hi>A.</hi> be an <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient Pariſh that hath Officers in it, and the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> be a Town within this Pariſh, which for a lo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> time hath been uſed, and reputed as a Par<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap> and hath all Parochial Rights, as Churchwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> here this place may be rated as <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Pariſh towards the Poor, <hi>Huttons Rep. fol.</hi> 93. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>M.</hi> 3 <hi>Car. B. R. Hilton &amp; Pauls</hi> Caſe, <hi>Cro.</hi> 3 <hi>p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap> Rep.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>This Tax muſt be ſet upon the Tenants and Occupiers of Lands; and nor upon the Land lords Living within or without the Pariſh; f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> the Tenant only is chargeable for the Land, <hi>B<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>
                           <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſtrods</hi> 1 <hi>part, Rep. fol.</hi> 354.</p>
                     <p>The Parſon having a full tenth Part of the Profits of the Place, may be rated to a tenth Part, <hi>Reſol. Judges</hi> 1633. <hi>ſect.</hi> 33.</p>
                     <p>He that doth occupy Lands in his own Hands lying in ſeveral Pariſhes, he muſt be charged in every Pariſh for his Land lying therein, only according to the proportion thereof, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> more; but for his perſonal Eſtate it ſeems rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable he ſhould be charged for it in the place where his Perſon is: All Lands Ancient De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meſn, Guildable and Copyhold, are to be charged with theſe Rates, which ought to be according to the value, or by the pound, and not according to the quantity, <hi>Sed conſuetud<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> tollit Legem.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="129" facs="tcp:96794:14"/>
The Rate for Stock or Goods is thought rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable to be ſet after the proportion of Lands, <hi>(viz.)</hi> an 100 pound in Stock to be rated after 5 or 6 pound a year in Land.</p>
                     <p>Note, That in ſome ſpecial Caſes a Man may be rated beyond his Ability; as where one brings a Charge upon a Pariſh; or under any pretence brings in a Man that may be chargeable in a Pariſh, he may, if there be cauſe for this, be raiſed in his Rate to the full value of his Eſtate; and ſo was the Opinion of Sir <hi>Nicholas Hide, Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 167.</p>
                     <p>Where the Inhabitants of any Pariſh are not able to relieve their Poor, any two Juſtices <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> may tax other Pariſhes and Places within the Hundred, yea, the whole Hundred, if need require; and where that is not ſufficient, the Juſtices in their Seſſions may tax the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty in part, or wholly at their diſcretion, 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2. <hi>Wingates Abr. Stat. Tit. Poor People,</hi> 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 12.</p>
                     <p>If any Perſons find themſelves aggrieved in any Tax, or other Act done by the Overſeers, or by the Juſtices of Peace, they are to be relieved at the Quarter Seſſions, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 160. <hi>Wingates Abr. Stat. Tit. Poor People.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>The Father, Grandfather, Mother, Grandmo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther and Children of every poor Perſon, ſhall be aſſeſſed towards their Relief, as the Juſtices of the Peace in their Seſſions of the Peace in the County where ſuch Father, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> dwells, ſhall limit and appoint, on pain to forfeit 20 <hi>s.</hi> a month, to the uſe of the Poor, to be levied by diſtreſs and ſale as aforeſaid, and for want of diſtreſs to be committed to Priſon till the
<pb n="130" facs="tcp:96794:15"/>
Forfeiture be paid, 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2. <hi>Wingates A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap> Stat. Tit. Poor People, Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>6.</p>
                     <p>Head Officers in Cities and Corporate Town and Aldermen of <hi>London,</hi> have in their ſever<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Precincts like Authority that Juſtices of Peace have in their Countles, and no other Juſtices of Peace are to enter and intermeddle there <hi>Wingates Abr. Stat. Tit. Poor People,</hi> 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2.</p>
                     <p>If any Pariſh ſhall extend into two Countles or part thereof to lie in any City or Corporate Town where they have Juſtices: Then the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices of every County, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are to intermeddle only within their own Limits; and every of them reſpectively within their Limits are in execute this Law concerning the nomination of Overſeers, binding of Apprentices, grant<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap> Warrants to levy Taxations, taking Accoun<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> of Overſeers, and committing ſuch as refuſe to account, or to pay their Arrearages; and yet the Overſeers ſhall without dividing themſelves, execute their Office in all places within the ſaid Pariſh, but ſhall give up Accounts to the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices, or Head Officers of both Places, <hi>Win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gates Abr. Stat. Tit. Poor People,</hi> 43. <hi>El. c.</hi> 2. <hi>Dalt J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 156.</p>
                     <p>Theſe Officers within four days after the en<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> of their Year (and that other Officers are no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minated) are to yield up a true Account to two Juſtices <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> of theſe things fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing, 1. What Sums of Mony they have re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, or rated and not received? 2. What ſtock of Ware or Stuff is in their Hands, or it the Hands of any of the Poor? 3. What Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices they have put out, and bound ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Statute? 4. What Poor they have ſet to work or relieved? 5. What Poor
<pb n="131" facs="tcp:96794:15"/>
they have ſuffered to wander and beg out of their Town, or in the Highways, or in their Town without their directions? 6. Whether they meet monthly to conſider of the things belonging to their Office? 7. Whether they made their Rates indifferent upon all Men, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to their Ability? 8. Whether they have endeavoured to gather and levy ſuch Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſsments? 9. Whether they have neglected the Juſtices Warrants to them, or any of them directed for the levying of any Forfeiture ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Stat. 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>ſ.</hi> 153.</p>
                     <p>By the Statute of 30 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. for Burying in Woollen, the Juſtices are not to allow the Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts of the Overſeers of the Poor, until they have given them an Account of the Burials and Certificates, and of their levying the Penalties in purſuance of that Act, 30 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 3.</p>
                     <p>Now if the Churchwardens, or Overſeers, or any of them, ſhall refuſe to make and yield a true and perfect Account to the ſaid Juſtices, of all ſuch Mony, and of all ſuch Stock as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, any two Juſtices <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> may com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit them to the common Gaol, there to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main without Bail, till they have made a true Account, and ſatisfied, and paid to the new Overſeers ſo much of the ſaid Sum or Stock, as upon the ſaid Account ſhall be remaining in his or their Hands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And if they make a falſe Account, they may be bound over to the Aſſizes or Seſſions, and there an Indictment may be preferred againſt them, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 154.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="132" facs="tcp:96794:16"/>
Alſo if any of the Churchwardens or Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeers ſhall refuſe, or deny to pay, or deliver over to the new Overſeers the Arrearages (Sums of Mony or Stock) which ſhall be in their Hands, and due, and behind upon their Account to be made as aforeſaid, any two ſuch Juſtices of Peace may make their Warrant to the preſent and ſubſequent Churchwardens and Overſeers, or any of them, to levy the ſame by diſtreſs and ſale of the Offenders Goods, rendring to the Parties the overplus, and in default of ſuch diſtreſs, any two Juſtices of the Peace may com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit him or them to the common Goal, there to remain without Ball, until-payment or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livery of the ſaid Sum, Arrearages and Stock be made, 42 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 154.</p>
                     <p>If any ſuch Stock ſhall be in the Hands of any of the Poor to work, and ſuch Poor ſhall refuſe to deliver the ſame, two ſuch Juſtices may make the like Warrant, to levy the ſame by diſtreſs, and for lack thereof, may commit ſuch Offenders to the Goal, as aforeſaid, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. ibid.</p>
                     <p>And for theſe aforeſaid, and all other Negli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gencies of the Churchwardens and Overſeers, in the Execution of their Office, about the Poor, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> every of them, for every Default, he makes, forfeits 20 <hi>s.</hi> which Default muſt be proved either by the Offenders own Confeſſion, or by Examination of Witneſſes, and it is to be le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vied by the new Churchwardens and Overſeers, or one of them, by Warrant from two Juſtices, as aforeſaid, by diſtreſs and ſale of the Offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders Goods; and for want of Diſtreſs, two ſuch Juſtices may commit Offenders to the Goal, there to remain without Bail, till the
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:96794:16"/>
ſaid Forfeitures ſhall be paid; which ſaid For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feitures are to be imployed to the uſe of the Poor of the ſaid Pariſh, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 73. <hi>f.</hi> 155. 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 2.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="6" type="chapter">
                     <head>CHAP. VI. <hi>The Overſeers Duty about Weights and Meaſures, and Burying in Woollen.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THere ſhall be one Weight, one Meaſure, and one Yard, according to the Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dard of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> throughout all the Realm, as well in places Priviledged, as with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out, and every Meaſure of Corn ſhall be ſtrik<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed without Heap: And whoſoever ſhall keep any other Weight, Meaſure, or Yard, whereby any Corn, Grain, or other thing is bought or ſold, ſhall forfeit for every Offence five ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, being thereof convicted, by the Oath of one ſufficient Witneſs, before any Juſtice of Peace, or Head-Officer of the City, Town, or Place where the Offence is done, to be levied by the Churchwardens or Overſeers of the Poor of the Pariſh, to the uſe of the Poor of the ſaid Pariſh, by Diſtreſs and Sale of the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders Goods, and for want of Diſtreſs, to be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>mpriſoned without Bail until payment. And all Perſons, upon Suit againſt him or them, for any thing done upon this Act, to plead the General Iſſue, and give the Act in Evidence, and to have treble Coſts, if unjuſtly vexed, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 112. <hi>f.</hi> 246. 17 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. 6. 19.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="134" facs="tcp:96794:17"/>
No Corps ſhall be buried in any thing other than what is made of Sheeps Wool only, or be put into any Coffin lined or faced with any thing made of any material but Sheeps Wool, on pain of the Forfeiture of five pounds, 30 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 3.</p>
                     <p>An Affidavit under the Hands and Seals of two Witneſſes (or under the Hand of the Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrate or Officer before whom it was ſworn, for which nothing ſhall be paid) muſt be brought to the Miniſter within eight days after the Party is interred, that he was not buried contrary to this Act, which ſhall be taken before ſome Juſtice of Peace, Maſter of Chancery, Ordinary or Extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ordinary, Mayor, Bailiff, or other chief Officer of the City, County, Borough, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> where the Party was buried: And if no ſuch Affidavit be brought, the Miniſter ſhall give notice thereof under his Hand to the Churchwardens or O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſeers of the Poor, who within eight days after ſhall repair to the Chief Magiſtrate in any Town, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> if buried there, elſe to a Juſtice of Peace, who upon Certificate thereof from the Miniſter, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall grant a Warrant for le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vying the Forfeiture by diſtreſs and ſale of the Goods of the Party deceaſed, or in default thereof, of the Perſons Goods in whoſe Houſe the Party died, or the Goods of any that had a Hand in putting ſuch Party into any Shroud, Coffin, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> contrary to this Act, or that or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered the ſame: And if ſuch Perſon were a Servant, and died in the Maſters Family, the Maſters Goods to be liable: And if ſuch Perſon died in his Parents Family, the Parents Goods to be liable: One Moiety of which Forfeiture ſhall be to the Poor of the Pariſh
<pb n="135" facs="tcp:96794:17"/>
where the Party is buried, the other to him that ſhall ſue for the ſame, 30 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 3.</p>
                     <p>Miniſters, Churchwardens, and Overſeers, Juſtices of Peace, or Chief Magiſtrates, neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lecting their Duty aforeſaid, ſhall forfeit five pounds for every Offence, to be recovered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> wherein the Proſecutor ſhall recover his full Coſts, ſo as the Suit be commenced, within ſix months after the Offence committed; one fourth part of the Forfeitures to the King; two fourth parts to the Poor of the Pariſh where the Offender dwells; and one fourth part to the Informer, 30 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 3.</p>
                     <p>Every Miniſter ſhall keep a Regiſter of all Burials and Affidavits: And where no Affidavit is brought as aforeſaid, ſhall enter a Memorial thereof againſt the Name of the Party interred, and of the time when he notified the ſame to the Churchwardens or Overſeers of the Poor. And the Overſeers when they give up their Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts at the Seſſions, or to any two Juſtices at their monthly Meetings, ſhall give an ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count of the Name and Quality of every Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon interred ſince their former Account; and of ſuch Certificates, and of their levying the Penalties, and of their diſpoſal thereof, on pain of five pounds to be levied by diſtreſs and ſale of Goods, by Warrant from the ſaid Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices, or two of them: and their Accounts ſhall not be allowed till they have accounted for their Burials, 30 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 3.</p>
                     <p>No Penalty ſhall be incurred where the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty died of the Plague: If any Perſon be proſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted, for what he ſhall do in purſuance to this Act, he may plead the General Iſſue, and give this
<pb n="136" facs="tcp:96794:18"/>
Act in Evidence: And upon a <hi>Nonſuit,</hi> Diſcon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuance or Verdict for him, or Judgment up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a Demurrer, he ſhall have treble Coſts, 30 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 3.</p>
                     <p>And now by the Statute of 32 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. (where no Juſtice of Peace ſhall reſide, or be to be found in any Pariſh where any Party ſhall be inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red) ſuch Oaths or Affidavits may be admin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtred, not only by ſuch Magiſtrates as aforeſaid, but by any Parſon, Vicar, or Curate in the ſame County, other than of the Pariſh or Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel of Eaſe where the Party is interred; and they are to atteſt the ſame under their Hands gratis, 32 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 1.</p>
                     <p>The Overſeers Duty about <hi>Iriſh</hi> Cattel, See <hi>Duty of Conſtables, ch.</hi> 8.</p>
                     <p>Their Duty in ſuppreſſing Conventicles, See <hi>Duty of Conſtables, ch.</hi> 9.</p>
                     <p>Note, That the Overſeers of the Poor, are to receive for the uſe of the Poor of the Pariſh where the Offence is committed, of ſuch who kill, or take in the night-time any Conies up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Borders of Warrens, or other Grounds lawfully uſed for keeping of Conies, except Owners, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or Perſons by them imployed, and of ſuch who uſe Snares, Harepipes, or other like Engines, or who take any Fiſh by any Net, Angle, or other Device whatſoever, in any Water or River, or ſhall be aſſiſting there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto, without conſent of the Lord, or Owner of the ſaid Water, what Sum the Juſtice of Peace before whom ſuch Offender ſhall be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>victed, ſhall think meet, not exceeding ten ſhillings (which he is to pay over and above re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compence to the Owner:) And in default of payment thereof, he that takes or kills ſuch
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:96794:18"/>
Conies, or uſeth Snares, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall be commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to the Houſe of Correction for any time not exceeding one month: And the Goods of him that takes ſuch Fiſh ſhall be liable to di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs; and for want of a Diſtreſs, he ſhall be committed to the Houſe of Correction, for any time not exceeding one month, unleſs he en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter into Bond with one or more Sureties to the Party injured, not exceeding ten pounds never to offend in like manner, 22 and 23 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 24.</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <body>
               <div type="guide_for_surveyors">
                  <pb facs="tcp:96794:19"/>
                  <pb n="139" facs="tcp:96794:19"/>
                  <head>A GUIDE FOR SURVEYORS OF High-ways and Bridges.</head>
                  <div n="1" type="chapter">
                     <head>CHAP. I. <hi>How many Sorts of ways there are; of the Choice of theſe Officers, with ſome few General Caſes concerning Highways.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>THere are three kind of Ways; Firſt, A Foot-way, called <hi>Iter, quod eſt jus eundi, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>vel ambulandi hominis.</hi> Secondly, a Foot-way and an Horſe-way, called <hi>actus, ab agendo,</hi> and this vulgarly is called a Pack or Drift-way, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>s both a Foot-way and Horſe-way. Thirdly, A Cart-way, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> called <hi>Via</hi> or <hi>Aditus,</hi> (and containeth the other two, and a Cart-way alſo) for this is <hi>jus eundi, vehendi, &amp; vehiculum &amp;</hi>
                        <pb n="140" facs="tcp:96794:20"/>
                        <hi>jumentum ducendi;</hi> and this is two-fold, <hi>viz<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Via Regia,</hi> The Kings High way for all Men, <hi>&amp; communis Strata,</hi> belonging to a City or Town, or between Neighbours.</p>
                     <p>It is called the Kings High-way, for that the King at all times hath therein Paſſage for Him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf and his People, and may puniſh all Nu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſances therein, though otherwiſe the Intereſt be in the Lord to bring his Action for dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging therein, or other like Treſpaſs there done, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 50. <hi>f.</hi> 101. and ſee <hi>Rolls</hi> Caſes, 1 <hi>part f.</hi> 392. 2 <hi>E.</hi> 4. 9. 8 <hi>E.</hi> 4. 9. 17 <hi>E.</hi> 3. <hi>f.</hi> 43. <hi>Bro Chemi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>e,</hi> 10, 11. <hi>&amp; Leet</hi> 3. 27 <hi>H.</hi> 6 <hi>f.</hi> 9. 8 <hi>H.</hi> 7. <hi>f.</hi> 5.</p>
                     <p>The High-way is not only the Common Tract, where Carts, Carriages, and People have gone; but if the Way be Foundrous, thi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> People cannot paſs in the Common Tract, and there be Out-lets out of it, into the Soll of another adjoyning, the People may in ſuch ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tremity uſe thoſe Out-lets upon anothers Soil, although it be ſowen with Corn: And that is, in ſuch caſe, the Kings High-way as well as the other; for the Kings Subjects muſt have a convenient Paſſage, as was reſolved in a Try<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> at Bar againſt Sir <hi>Henry Du<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>comb, Tr.</hi> 10 <hi>Car. Rolls</hi> 1 <hi>part of Abridgment, fol.</hi> 390. Therefore where a Way goes through a Mans Land, and the Owner of the Land Fence it on both ſides<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> he, by ſo doing, hath made himſelf liable to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pair the High-way, and keep it paſſable; and it is not ſufficient for him to keep it in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> good repair, as it was at the time of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cloſure; for by ſo doing he hath ſtraitned the High-way, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 50. <hi>f.</hi> 98.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="141" facs="tcp:96794:20"/>
The Conſtables and Churchwardens of every Pariſh ſhall yearly, upon <hi>Tueſday</hi> or <hi>Wedneſday</hi> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>n <hi>Eaſter</hi> Week, call together a number of the Pariſhioners, and then make choice of two of the Pariſh to be Surveyors of the High-ways the Year following, who ſhall forthwith take that Office upon them, on pain to forfeit twenty ſhillings a piece, 2 &amp; 3. <hi>Ph.</hi> &amp; <hi>Mar. c.</hi> 8.</p>
                     <p>The Conſtables and Churchwardens are then alſo to appoint ſix days betwixt that and the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>our and twentieth day of <hi>June,</hi> for the amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent of the High ways, and to give publick no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice thereof in the Church the next Sunday after, 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M. c.</hi> 8. &amp; 5 <hi>El. c.</hi> 13.</p>
                     <p>High-ways muſt be ſufficiently amended at the charge of the whole Town: And it is not enough for the Inhabitants to do their full ſix days work yearly; except their Ways be all well and ſufficiently repaired thereby: For if all their ſaid Ways be not ſufficiently amended, the whole Town may be indicted therefore, and if ſix days work in the year will not ſerve to amend them, the Surveyors may, yea, muſt ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point more days, <hi>Dalt. P. J. c.</hi> 50. <hi>f.</hi> 101.</p>
                     <p>The Owner of Lands, if he be not the Occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pier thereof, ought not to be charged towards the repair of the com<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>on High ways; but the Tenant who occupies the Lands is to be charged <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ill.</hi> 1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>Car.</hi> 1. <hi>Br.</hi> in one <hi>Foſters</hi> Caſe, <hi>per Curiam, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>lls Caſes,</hi> 1 <hi>part, f.</hi> 390.</p>
                     <p>All Fines and Forfeitures aſſeſſed in the Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, upon the Statute 5 <hi>El.</hi> about High-ways, muſt be Eſtreated by the Clerk of the Peace, and muſt be levled, accounted, and imployed as is appointed by the 2 &amp; 3 <hi>Ph.</hi> &amp; <hi>Mar. c.</hi> 8. 5 <hi>El. c.</hi> 13.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="142" facs="tcp:96794:21"/>
The Surveyors upon Warrant from two Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices of Peace, are to levy by diſtreſs and ſale of Goods, the Forfeitures of all ſuch Perſons as offend againſt the 18 <hi>El.</hi> 10. in not Scowring their Ditches, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and if they neglect by the ſpace of a year after the Offence committed, to levy the Forfeiture; Then the Juſtices may ſend to the Conſtable and Churchwardens to levy the ſame, 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 10.</p>
                     <p>By the Stat. 22 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 12. All Conſtables and Surveyors of the High-ways ſhall put in exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution the Statutes for repairing and inlarging High-ways, and levy the Penalties thereby im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed. And every Conſtable or Surveyor of the High-ways neglecting ſo to do, or wilfully ſuffering any Waggons or Carts to paſs through his Limits, with any more Horſes or Cattel, or in any other manner than this Act alloweth, upon Conviction thereof by one Oath before one Juſtice, or the Juſtices own view, ſhall pay ſuch Fine (not exceeding 40 <hi>s.)</hi> as ſuch Juſtice ſhall Aſſeſs.</p>
                     <p>All Actions brought againſt any Perſon for acting by this Law, ſhall be laid in the proper County, and Defendants may plead the General Iſſue, and recover treble Coſts.</p>
                     <p>No travelling Waggon, Cart, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in which any Burdens ſhall be carried, (except Carts uſed about Husbandry, and carrying Hay, Straw, Co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> unthraſhed, Coal, Chalk, Timber for Shippi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> or Building, Stones of all ſorts, Ammunition o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Artillery for the King) ſhall be drawn, or go i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> any Road or publick High way, with above five Horſe-beaſts at length, and if any draw with more Horſes or Oxen, he ſhall draw all two a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> breaſt, except one Horſe.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="143" facs="tcp:96794:21"/>
Every Owner of any Waggon, Cart, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Horſe <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>r Beaſts, ſhall forfeit for every Offence 40 <hi>s.</hi> one <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hird part to the Surveyors to amend the Ways; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ne third part to the Overſeers for the Poor; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he laſt third part to him who ſhall diſcover <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he Offender.</p>
                     <p>The Surveyor, where any neglect to come <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>d labour, ſhall complain thereof to the next <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>aſtices, who upon Oath of one Witneſs, ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap>y for every days labour neglected 18 <hi>d.</hi> and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>or every Man and Horſe 3 <hi>s.</hi> and for every Cart <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ith two Men 10 <hi>s.</hi> for each day neglecting, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 12.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="2" type="chapter">
                     <head>CHAP. II. <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>e Duty of the Surveyors about Setting and Cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling the Pariſhioners to the common days works for the High-ways, and about taking and dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing for Gravel, Chalk, Sand,</hi> &amp;c.</head>
                     <p>THeſe Officers are to ſee that the Pariſhio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners do their Work on the days appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>d, and that according to theſe Rules following, <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>iz.</hi> Every Perſon having in his own Occupa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>on a Plough Land in Tillage, or in Paſture in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>e ſame Pariſh, or keeping there a Plough or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>raught, ſhall find and ſend on every day to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>e place appointed by the Surveyors, one <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ain or Cart provided, after the Faſhion of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he Country, with Oxen, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> fit for the Carri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ge, and with neceſſary Tools fit for the Work, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>nd with two able Men, who are there to do <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>ch Work with their Wains, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as they ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>e appointed (by the Surveyors) by the ſpace
<pb n="144" facs="tcp:96794:22"/>
of eight hours every of the ſaid ſix days, on pain of 10 <hi>s.</hi> every day default is made, 2, 4 P. <hi>M. c.</hi> 8. <hi>Raſtall.</hi> 199. <hi>Lamb.</hi> 459. <hi>Wingates Abr. Stat. Tit. High-ways, Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 50. <hi>f.</hi> 102.</p>
                     <p>And every other Houſholder, Cottager, and Labourer of the Pariſh, Town, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> (able to la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour, and being no hired Servant by the year) muſt by himſelf, or ſome other able Man, be then and there ready to work every of the ſaid ſix days, by the ſpace of eight hours, as aforeſaid, where they ſhall be appointed by the Surveyors, under pain to forfeit 12 <hi>d.</hi> for every day they make default, 2, 3 <hi>P. M. c.</hi> 8.</p>
                     <p>Note, That all Perſons being chargeable but as Cottagers, by the 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P. M</hi> yet if they be in Subſidy 5 <hi>l.</hi> in Goods, or 40 <hi>s.</hi> in Lands, or above, they muſt find two able Men to work every of the ſaid ſix days, 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 10. <hi>Wingates Abr. Stat Tit. High-ways.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>If any of the Carriages ſhall not be thought needful by the ſaid Surveyors upon any of the ſaid days, they may appoint inſtead of a Team, two able Men to work as aforeſaid, who ſhall not fail on pain that the Party that ſhould ſend them, ſhall forfeit 12 pence for every day that either of them make default, <hi>Wingates Abr. Stat. Tit. High-ways,</hi> 2, 3 <hi>P. M. c.</hi> 8. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 50. <hi>f.</hi> 100.</p>
                     <p>He that ſhall occupy a Plow land in Tillage or Paſture, lying in ſeveral Pariſhes, ſhall be chargeable only in the Pariſh where he dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leth; and he that occupieth ſeveral Plow-lands in ſeveral Pariſhes, ſhall be charged in each Town or Pariſh where ſuch Land lieth (to wit) to find in each Town or Pariſh one Cart fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed
<pb n="145" facs="tcp:96794:22"/>
as aforeſaid, though he be no Inhabitant there, 10 <hi>El. c.</hi> 18. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 50. <hi>f</hi> 99.</p>
                     <p>Now for the further opening of theſe things, note, That it is ſaid, that a Plow land is not of any certain Contents, but ordinarily it is ſo much as one Plough may Plough in one day, which in ſome Countries is more, and in ſome leſs, according to the heavineſs of the Soil, <hi>Co.</hi> 9 <hi>Rep. f.</hi> 124. <hi>Co.</hi> on <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>it. f.</hi> 69. <hi>&amp; vide Lamb. ver. Hide</hi> 35 <hi>H</hi> 6. <hi>f</hi> 29.</p>
                     <p>And note, That a Plow land, or Carve of Land may cont<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>in Houſe, Meadow, Paſture and Wood: And if one have ſo much of this as will keep a Plough, and yield Tillage for it, if part of it were eared, in this caſe it ſeems he is to ſend his Plough, <hi>Vide Co.</hi> 4 <hi>Rep f.</hi> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>. <hi>&amp;</hi> 9 <hi>Rep. f.</hi> 122.</p>
                     <p>He that hath a Plough <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>nd, and no Plough, but doth ſuffer his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>and to lie freſh, yet he is to f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>nd a Plough for this Work; and ſo it hath been agreed by the Judges, <hi>Mich.</hi> 21 <hi>Jac. Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 50. <hi>f.</hi> 105.</p>
                     <p>He that keepeth a Plough, or Draught for Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage, although he occupieth little or no Land, but carrieth or plougheth for other Men, yet it ſeems he is to ſend his Cart to the High ways; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>d if a Man keep only two Horſes and a Cart for his own Buſineſs, in this caſe it ſeems he is to come with his Cart and two Horſes, with a Man <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>o manage them, <hi>Vide D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>lt J. P. c.</hi> 50. ibid.</p>
                     <p>It is held by ſome, that ſo many Ploughs or Draughts Men have, and uſe frequently about their own Buſineſs in Summer, ſo many they are <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>o bring with them to the High-ways; ſo that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>f a Man have one Plough and five or ſix Horſes, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>nd ſhall Plough ſeven or eight ſcore Acres of and, and ſhall uſually go in the Summer time
<pb n="146" facs="tcp:96794:23"/>
with two Carts or Draughts; in this caſe it ſeems he is to come with two Carts or Draughts to this Service: And he that occupieth 40 or 50 Acres of Land, and keepeth only three Horſes, and one Draught or Cart, he is to come with one Draught or Cart, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 50. <hi>f.</hi> 105.</p>
                     <p>Theſe Officers may, if they ſee cauſe, for the amendment of the High-ways, take and carry away ſo much of the Rubbiſh, and ſmalleſt broken Stones already digged, of any Mans Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry lying within the ſame Pariſh, without leave of the Owner, as they ſhall think needful, or gather the looſe Stones lying diſperſed in any Mans Grounds; but they may not without Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cence dig in any Mans Quarry for new Stones, nor take the great Stones already digged; and if there be no ſuch Rubbiſh to be found in any Mans Quarry within the ſaid Pariſh, then may they enter into any Mans ſeveral Ground within the Pariſh, lying near the place where the Ways are decayed, and there (if they ſee any hopes of finding Materials fit for the Reparation there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of) without leave of the Owner, they may dig for Sand, Stones, Gravel, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſo that it be not i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> the Houſes, Gardens, Orchards, or Meadows of any Man; for they are not to come there with out Licence of the Owner; and in ſuch place where they may dig without leave, they are no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> to make a Pit above ten yards in breadth <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> length, and they are to take care that the place be filled up again at the charge of the Pariſh within one month after, upon pain to forfel five Marks to the Owner of the Ground, to be recovered by Action of Debt; and this by th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>El. c.</hi> 13.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="3" type="chapter">
                     <pb n="147" facs="tcp:96794:23"/>
                     <head>CHAP. III. <hi>The Surveyors Duty about cutting down Buſhes, Trees, and ſcouring of Ditches in the High-ways; and alſo touching Preſentments and Inquiries about Defaults, paſſing of Accounts, Travelling of Wagons, Wains,</hi> &amp;c.</head>
                     <p>IF the Owners of the Grounds, next adjoyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the High-ways, do not keep their Hedges low, and cut down their Trees and Buſhes growing in the ſame ways, they ſo feit ten ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>Wingates Abr. Stat. Tit. High-ways,</hi> 5 <hi>El. c.</hi> 13. 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 10.</p>
                     <p>And he that ſcours not his Ditches in the Ground next adjoyning to the Ground that is next the High-ways, to the end the Water may have the better paſſage out of the High-ways, ſhall forfeit 12 pence for every Rod ſo left un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcoured, 18 <hi>E. c</hi> 10. <hi>Wingate, ut ſupra.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>If any ſcour his Ditch by the High way ſide, and throw the ſcouring thereof into the High-way, and ſuffer it to lie there ſix months, he for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feits for every Load thereof 12 pence; and the Surveyors are to make Sluces where ſuch Banks have been heretoſore made, for carrying away the Water out of the High-way, 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 10.</p>
                     <p>Every Surveyor may cauſe any Water-courſe, or Spring of Water in the High-way, (within their Pariſh) to be turned into another Mans ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Ditch or Ground next adjoyning to the ſaid Way, in ſuch manner as by the diſcretion of the ſaid Surveyor ſhall be thought meet, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 50. <hi>f.</hi> 103.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="148" facs="tcp:96794:24"/>
Note, That the Forfei<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ures of the Act of the 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 10. muſt be levied by the Surveyors for the time being, (by Warrant from the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>uſtice<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> before whom the Party ſhall be convict) by Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs and Sale of Goods; which Forfeitures a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> to be employed towards the amendment of the High-ways; and if the Surveyors neglect to do it within one year after the Offence committed then the Conſtables and Churchwardens by like Warrant may do it, 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 10. <hi>Wingates Abr. Stat. Tit. High-ways.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>The Surveyors, or one of them, are to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent to the next Juſtice of Peace every Defaul<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> upon the 2 <hi>&amp;</hi> 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M. c.</hi> 8. &amp; 5 <hi>El.</hi> c. 14. with in one month after it ſhall be made, on pain o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 40 <hi>s.</hi> and the Juſtice is on pain of 5 <hi>l</hi> to cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifie the ſame at the next Quarter Seſſions, where the Juſtices have power to inquire of the Default, and ſhall ſet ſuch Fine upon the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>linquents, as they, or two of them <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> ſhall think fit, 5 <hi>El. c.</hi> 13.</p>
                     <p>That the Preſentment of a Juſtice of Pea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> in Seſſions, upon his own Knowledge ſhall be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> good Conviction, whereupon the Juſtices in Se<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſions, or any two of them <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> may aſſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> a Fine, as well as upon a Verdict of twelve Me<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> but in this caſe the Delinquent ſhall be admit<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ted to his Traverſe, as in other Caſes, 5 <hi>El. c.</hi> 1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>vide Raſtal.</hi> 199.</p>
                     <p>The Defaul<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>s and Offences upon theſe Statute 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> 5 <hi>El.</hi> &amp; 18 <hi>El.</hi> are inquirable b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> the Juſtices of Peace in their Seſſions, or b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Stewards in Leets, either of which have powe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> to ſet Fines upon Offenders at their diſcret<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ons; of which Fines, indented Eſtreats (<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> the Seſſions under the Hand and Seal of t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <pb n="149" facs="tcp:96794:24"/>
Clerk of the Peace, in the Leet, under the Hand and Seal of the Steward) ſhall be delivered within ſix weeks after <hi>Michaelmas,</hi> one part of the Eſtreat to the Bailiff or High Conſtable of the Liberty, and the other part to the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles and Churchwardens of the Pariſh where the Offe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ders live, 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M. c.</hi> 8. 5 <hi>El. c.</hi> 13. 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 10. <hi>Wingates Abr. Stat. Tit. High-ways.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>And theſe Eſtreats ſhall be a ſufficient War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant for the Bailiff, or Chief Conſtable of the liberty of levy the ſaid Offences by way of Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs; and if no Diſtreſs can be found, or the Party do not pay the Fine within 20 days after <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>awful demand thereof, he or they ſhall forfeit double ſo much; all which Fines and Forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ures are to be employed, and beſtowed towards the amendment of the High-ways in the Pariſh where the Offences are committed, <hi>Wingates Abr. Stat. Tit. High-ways,</hi> 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M. c.</hi> 8.</p>
                     <p>The Balliff, or High Conſtable, ſhall yearly be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>wixt the firſt of <hi>March,</hi> and laſt of <hi>April,</hi> render <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>o Account unto the Conſtables and Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens, who have the other parts of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ſtreats of the Fines, of what Mony they have <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>eceived, on pain of 40 <hi>s.</hi> and the ſaid Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>les and Churchwardens have power to call the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ailiff or High Conſtable before two or more <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>ſtices of the Peace <hi>(Quor. unus)</hi> to paſs his Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ount, who have power to commit him, until he <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ave ſatisfied all the Arrearages by him re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>eived, ſave 8 <hi>d.</hi> in the pound for his own Fee, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>od 12 <hi>d.</hi> in the pound for the Clerk of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>eace, or Steward of the Leet, and in this caſe the (<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>cceeding Conſtables and Churchwardens have <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he ſame power as their Predeceſſors had, 2 &amp; 3 <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>. &amp; <hi>M. c.</hi> 8.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="150" facs="tcp:96794:25"/>
Two Juſtices of the Peace by the Stat. 18 <hi>El.</hi> may take Accounts of the Surveyors of the Ways, and the Petty Conſtables and Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens, for ſuch Forfeitures (within that Statute) as they have levied, 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 10 <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 50. <hi>f.</hi> 103.</p>
                     <p>Note, There are ſeveral Statutes which con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern particular High-ways, in which theſe Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors are little concerned; I ſhall therefore only name the Statutes, and they who deſire to be further informed therein, may look the Statutes at large.</p>
                     <p>Stat. 39 <hi>El. c.</hi> 10. for repairing the High-ways in the Wild of <hi>Suſſex, Surry</hi> and <hi>Kent,</hi> uſed for Iron Works. Stat. 37 <hi>H</hi> 8. <hi>c.</hi> 3. For <hi>Huntington Lane</hi> near to <hi>Cheſter.</hi> Stat. 14 <hi>H</hi> 8. <hi>c.</hi> 6. &amp; 26 <hi>H.</hi> 8. <hi>c.</hi> 7. For laying out new High-ways in the Wild of <hi>Kent</hi> or <hi>Suſſex.</hi> Stat. 1 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 5. for the Cauſway between <hi>Dorcheſter</hi> and <hi>Sherborn.</hi> Stat. 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 10. about the Kings Ferry in <hi>Kent.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="4" type="chapter">
                     <head>CHAP. IV. <hi>Some Heads of the Stat.</hi> 22 &amp; 23 Car. 2. <hi>c.</hi> 17. <hi>concerning the Ways, Sewers, Pavements,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>in</hi> London, <hi>and the Scavengers Office.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>BY the Stat. of 22 &amp; 23 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. A Clauſe <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>o a late Act of Parliament, Entituled, <hi>A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> Act for Rebuilding the City of</hi> London; wherein was Enacted, That the Numbers and Places for Common Sewers, Drains and Vaults, and the manner of Paving and Pitching Streets and Lanes in the ſaid City and Liberties, ſhould be ſet ou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> by Perſons appointed by the Mayor, Aldermen
<pb n="151" facs="tcp:96794:25"/>
and Common Council, or ſeven or more of them, together with the Surveyors, or one of them within the Precincts reſpectively, which Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, or ſeven, or more of them were impowred to impoſe Taxes upon Houſes in proportion to the benefit they receive thereby, and to levy the ſame by Diſtreſs and Sale of Goods, is made perpetual, together with the Powers thereby given and appointed to be executed: And the ſole Powers of ordering and regula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting the keeping clear, pitching and paving the Streets, Lanes and Paſſages, with the manner thereof, and of making and cleanſing Drains and Sewers in <hi>London,</hi> is to remain in the Mayor, Commonalty, and Citizens, to be executed by ſuch as the Mayor, Aldermen and Commons in Common Council ſhall appoint, or ſeven or more of them being all Members of the ſaid Court. And Perſons imployed in any of the ſaid Works, are enjoyned to obſerve the Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rections of the Perſons in that behalf authorized, 22 &amp; 23 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 17.</p>
                     <p>Offenders may be proceeded againſt by In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictment at the next Seſſions of the Peace, in the ſaid City and Liberties, unleſs they ſubmit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to the Cenſure of the Perſons ſo authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zed, or any ſeven or more of them, and pay the Mulct by them impoſed to the Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of <hi>London,</hi> to be imployed towards the Works in this Act mentioned, 22 &amp; 23 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 17.</p>
                     <p>The Perſons ſo authorized may impoſe Taxes on the ſeveral Wards and Precincts, and direct Precepts to the reſpective Deputies and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Council Men to aſſeſs the ſame, and like Precepts to Scavengers to collect the ſame: And
<pb n="152" facs="tcp:96794:26"/>
where any Church or Churchyard ſhall front or adjoyn to any of the ſaid Streets, Lanes or Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſages, they may aſſeſs a reaſonable proportion upon the Pariſh to be paid by the Churchwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens, of which Aſſeſsments the Deputies and Common Council Men ſhall return Duplicates with the Scavengers Names, within twenty days after receipt of the Precepts. And in default of the ſaid Deputies, and Common Council Men the ſaid Perſons to be authorized may rate the ſaid Aſſeſsments. And in default of payment within ſix days after demand, the Scavengers may levy the ſame by diſtreſs and ſale of Goods, rendring the overplus, beſides the reaſonable Charge of diſtraining: And the Mony ſo col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected ſhall be paid into the Chamber of <hi>London,</hi> not to be iſſued thence, but by order of the ſaid Perſons ſo to be appointed, or ſeven or more of them, 22 &amp; 23 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 17.</p>
                     <p>Inhabitants aggrieved through defect or decay of Pavements, or want of cleanſing the Streets, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall upon proof that ſuch grievance is un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reformed, receive directions from the Perſons ſo to be authorized, or ſeven or m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>re of them, for redreſſing the ſame, and a Warrant under their Hands and Seals to the Chamberlain of <hi>London</hi> to iſſue Monies for defraying the Charge thereof, together with any Sum not exceeding ten ſhillings for encouragement of his or their Diligence, who upon receipt of ſuch Warrant ſhall pay the ſame accordingly: And Perſons aggrieved by any Charge impoſed by virtue of this Act, within five days after demand there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, may appeal to the Mayor and Court of Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dermen, whoſe Order therein ſhall be final, 22 &amp; 23 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 17.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="153" facs="tcp:96794:26"/>
The Mayor, Aldermen and Commons in Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Council may ſet out and purchaſe Ground for Layſtals, and places for publick Stores, for receipt of Dirt and Rubbiſh carried out of the City, and for other Materials and Commodities. The Mony for the ſame to be paid out of the Monies ariſing by the Impoſition upon Coals ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed for publick Uſes of the City, other than the Mony appointed for Building Churches, 22 &amp; 23 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 17.</p>
                     <p>No Perſons by this Act made liable to be rated towards the altering, mending, or clean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing the ſaid Vaults, Sewers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or cleanſing, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Streets, Lanes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall be otherwiſe charged or liable thereunto, 22 &amp; 23 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 17.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="5" type="chapter">
                     <head>CHAP. V. <hi>Some Heads of the</hi> 2 <hi>of</hi> W. <hi>and</hi> M. <hi>for Paving and Cleanſing the Streets in the Cities of</hi> London <hi>and</hi> Weſtminſter, <hi>Suburbs and Liberties there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, the Out-Pariſhes in the County of</hi> Middleſex, <hi>the Borough of</hi> Southwark, <hi>and other Places within the Weekly Bills of Mortality, in the County of</hi> Surrey.</head>
                     <p>EVery Inhabitant inhabiting in the ſaid Pariſhes, and in the Town of <hi>Kenſington,</hi> ſhall twice every Week ſweep before their Houſes and Buildings, and take up the Dirt ready for the Scavenger, or other Officer, or elſe for every Offence or Neglect, forfeit 3 <hi>s.</hi> 4 <hi>d.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="154" facs="tcp:96794:27"/>
If any throw, or permit to be thrown, Aſhes, Filth, or Annoyance before his Houſe, Build<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing or Wall, ſhall forfeit 5 <hi>s.</hi> If before any Church, Church yard, or publick Buildings, or into any Sink, or Way, publick or private; but ſhall keep it in their Houſes and Yards, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>til, the Officers come to carry it away, or elſe forfeit 20 <hi>s.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Churchwardens, Houſe-keepers of <hi>White-hall,</hi> or other the Kings Houſes, or of Noblemens Houſes, ſhall be ſubject to like Penalty; ſo ſhall Uſhers of Courts, and Porters, and Keepers of other publick Buildings.</p>
                     <p>Scavengers and Officers ſhall come every day (except Sundays and Holidays) and give no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice that the Parties concerned may bring out their Duſt, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or forfeit 40 <hi>s.</hi> for every neglect.</p>
                     <p>Every Houſholder ſhall pave, and keep re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paired the Streets before their Houſes and Ground unto the Chann<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>l, or elſe forfeit for every Rod 20 <hi>s.</hi> and 20 <hi>s.</hi> every Week until it ſhall be ſufficiently repaired.</p>
                     <p>Where new Streets and Ways are made, which the Juſtices of Peace in their General Quarter-Seſſions ſhall think fi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> and convenient to be paved with Stone or Gravel, and ſhall order the ſame to be done before every dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling Houſe or Building in ſuch Street or Way; Every Perſon neglecting, ſhall forfeit forty ſhillings for every ſuch Offence, for every Perch, and after that rate, for a greater or leſſer quantity, and the like Sum for every Week till the ſame be paved and amended.</p>
                     <p>Where Streets, Lanes or Allies have been by Cuſtom otherwiſe repaired, it ſhall be done
<pb n="155" facs="tcp:96794:27"/>
by ſuch Perſons as are by Cuſtom to do it, under the Penalties aforeſaid.</p>
                     <p>Upon <hi>Monday</hi> or <hi>Tueſday</hi> in <hi>Eaſter</hi> Week, The Conſtables, Churchwardens, Overſeers and Surveyors giving notice, and calling ſuch Inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitants that have ſerved that Office, ſhall chuſe two Tradeſmen to be Scavengers; who being allowed under the Hand of any two Juſtices, ſhall within ſeven days take the Office, or pay 10 <hi>l.</hi> and within ſeven days after ſuch refuſal, they ſhall in like manner chuſe another, who ſhall accept, or pay 10 <hi>l.</hi> which Penalties to be le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vied by Diſtreſs and Sale, and for want of Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs or Payment within ſix days after notice at his Houſe, to be ſent to the Goal until pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. Within twenty days after ſuch Election, the Conſtables, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall call ſuch Inhabitants as have born the like Office, and make a Tax by a Pound Rate, which being confirmed by two Juſtices, ſhall be quarterly paid upon de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand made by the Scavengers, or other Officers appointed to gather the ſame, and being refuſed, ſhall by Warrant of two Juſtices be levied by Diſtreſs and Sale, and for want of Diſtreſs, by Impriſonment of the Offender until payment. The Scavengers are to account for the Mony by them Collected, to two Juſtices of the Peace, within twenty eight days after new Scavengers are Elected, and to pay what Mony remains in their Hands to the new Scavengers.</p>
                     <p>The Scavengers and Rakers for any of the ſaid Pariſhes ſhall have liberty, by the Order of the Juſtices in the Petty-Seſſions, or any two of them, to lodge their Soil in ſuch va<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cant places near the Streets or High-ways, a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> ſhall be thought convenient by the ſaid Juſtices,
<pb n="156" facs="tcp:96794:28"/>
for the accommodation of the Country Carts returning empty from the ſaid Pariſhes, they giving ſatisfaction to the Owners of ſuch vacant places, and in caſe of unreaſonable Demands, the Juſtices in their Petty-Seſſions may hear and moderate the ſame. If any Perſons find them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves aggrieved with the ſtates made by virtue of this Act, or any ways prejudiced by the determination of the Juſtices in their Petty-Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions, they may have recourſe to the Juſtices at their General Quarter-Seſſions of the Peace.</p>
                     <p>And whereas there are many Common High-ways within the ſaid Pariſhes, which cannot be ſufficiently repaired by means of the Laws now in force, an Aſſeſsment may be made upon all the Inhabitants, Owners and Occupiers of Lands and Houſes, or perſonal Eſtate uſually ratable to the Poor within any of the ſaid Pariſhes, to be collected by ſuch Perſons as the Juſtices ſhall appoint at their General Quarter-Seſſions, the Mony ſo collected, to be employed as the Ju<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſtices ſhall direct towards repairing the ſaid High-ways.</p>
                     <p>No ſuch Rate ſhall exceed four pence in the Pound, in any one year, in the yearly value of Lands, Houſes or Tenements, nor of eight pence for every twenty pounds in perſonal Eſtate.</p>
                     <p>No Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, ſhall ſuffer his Waggon, Cart or Car to ſtand in the <hi>Hay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>market</hi> near <hi>Pickadilly</hi> in the Pariſh of St. <hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tin</hi> in the Fields, St. <hi>James</hi> within the Liberty of <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> Borough of <hi>Southwark,</hi> or any other place in the Pariſhes within the Weekly Bills of Mortality, loaden with Hay or Straw, to ſell the ſame from <hi>Michaelmas</hi> to <hi>Lady-day,</hi> after two of the Clock in the Afternoon, and
<pb n="157" facs="tcp:96794:28"/>
from <hi>Lady-day</hi> to <hi>Michaelmas,</hi> after one in the Afternoon, on pain to forfeit five ſhillings for every Offence and Neglect.</p>
                     <p>The Owners and Proprietors of any Cart, Car or Dray, the Wheels whereof ſhall not be made ſix Inches in the breadth, or ſhall be ſhod with Iron, or be drawn with above two Horſes, ſhall forfeit forty ſhillings for every time ſuch Cart, Car or Dray ſhall be uſed, for the uſes; and to be levied as aforeſaid: This ſhall not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to any Country Cart or Waggon that ſhall bring any Goods to the Cities or Places afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, or ſhall carry any Goods half a Mile be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yond the paved Streets of the ſaid Cities and Places.</p>
                     <p>One Juſtice of Peace upon View or Confeſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, or Oath of one Witneſs, may convict any of the Offences aforeſaid, if Conviction be up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on proof, one Moiety to the Overſeers of the Poor, for the Relief of the Poor of the Place where the Offence was committed, the other Moiety to him that ſhall diſcover and proſecute the ſame. But if the Conviction ſhall be by the View, then one half to the Poor, the other towards repairing and cleanſing the Streets, to be paid to the Scavengers of the Place, to be levied by the Juſtices Warrant under Hand and Seal, to the Conſtable, by Diſtreſs and Sale, or for want of Diſtreſs or Payment within ſix days after notice at the Houſe, to be ſent to Goal without Bail, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> payment.</p>
                     <p>No Perſon (within the Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and Liberties of the ſame, Borough of <hi>Southwark,</hi> and Pariſhes aforeſaid) ſhall breed, feed or keep any Swine in any Houſes or Backſides of the paved Streets where the
<pb n="158" facs="tcp:96794:29"/>
Houſes are contiguous, on pain to forfeit the ſame to the Churchwardens and Overſeers of the Poor of the Pariſh where ſuch Swine ſhall be kept, to the uſe of the Poor.</p>
                     <p>The Churchwardens, Chappel-wardens, Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeers of the Poor, Conſtables, Beadles, Head-boroughs or Tythingmen of any the Pariſhes in the ſaid Cities and Places reſpectively, in the day-time, with a Warrant under the Hand and Seal of the Lord Mayor, or any other of their Majeſties Juſtices of the Peace, may ſearch for ſuch Swine, and if any be found, they may ſeize and carry them away, and ſell them for the beſt price that can be had, and diſtribute the Mony to the Poor of the Pariſh where they were ſeized.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="6" type="chapter">
                     <head>CHAP. VI. <hi>Several Caſes about the Repairs of Bridges, with the Names of the Statutes which concern parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular Bridges.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>WHere a Common Bridge in the Kings High-way is in decay, and that it can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be proved or known, who, nor what Lands are chargeable to the repairing thereof; in this caſe four Juſtices of the Peace (whereof one to be of the <hi>Quorum)</hi> within the Shire or Riding wherein ſuch decayed Bridges be; and if they be in a City, or Town Corporate, then <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> ſuch Juſtices of Peace there, may within the Limits of their ſeveral Commiſſions, call before them the Conſtables, or two of the moſt honeſt Inhabitants of every Town and Pariſh within
<pb n="159" facs="tcp:96794:29"/>
the Shire, Riding, City or Town Corporate, wherein ſuch Bridge, or any parcel thereof ſhall happen to be; and the Juſtices (upon the appearance of the Conſtables, or other Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants, and with their Aſſents) may Tax every Inhabitant in any ſuch City, Town or Pariſh within their Limits, to ſuch reaſonable Sum of Mony as by their Diſcretions they ſhall think convenient, as well for the repairing of ſuch Bridge, and alſo for the making and repairing of the High-ways by the ſpace of 300 Foot next adjoyning to the Ends of any ſuch Bridges, 22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. <hi>c.</hi> 5. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 16. <hi>f.</hi> 44. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 701, 702.</p>
                     <p>But Note, Where the Franchiſe, City or Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rough is a County of it ſelf, and hath not four or more Juſtices of the Peace, whereof one or more are of the <hi>Quorum,</hi> in this caſe no other Juſtices of the Peace, of any Shire or County, have any power to meddle there by this Act, but ſuch decay muſt be reformed by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Law, by ſuch Remedy as they were be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the making of the Statute of 22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 702.</p>
                     <p>And note, That this Taxation ought not to be made by the Juſtices, without the Conſent of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he Conſtables or Inhabitants, nor by them without the Juſtices; and this Tax ought to be upon every Inhabitant in particular, and not to be ſet upon the Hundred, Pariſh, Town, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for then one or two might be diſtrained upon for the whole, <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 704.</p>
                     <p>After ſuch Taxation made, as aforeſaid, the ſaid Juſtices of Peace ſhall cauſe the Names and Sums of every particular Perſon ſo by them taxed, to be written in a Roll indented in Parch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment
<pb n="160" facs="tcp:96794:30"/>
for every Hundred, and ſealed with their Seals, <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. fol.</hi> 704. <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 16. ibid.</p>
                     <p>And the ſaid Juſtices may make two Colle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctors of every Hundred, for the Collecting of all ſuch Sums of Mony by the ſaid Juſtices ſet and taxed, which Collectors receiving the one part of the Roll indented, have power thereby to collect all the Sums of Mony therein contained, and if refuſal be made upon demand, then to diſtrain, and ſell ſuch Diſtreſs, rendring the overplus to the Owner, if any be, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 16. <hi>f.</hi> ibid. 22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. <hi>c.</hi> 5. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt f.</hi> 705.</p>
                     <p>The ſaid Juſtices alſo are to appoint two Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors, who ſhall ſee ſuch decayed Bridges and Ways repaired and amended from time to time as often as need ſhall require, to whoſe Hands the Collectors muſt pay the Monies by them re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 16. ibid. 22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. <hi>c.</hi> 5.</p>
                     <p>And the ſaid Collectors and Surveyors, and their Executors and Adminiſtrators, and every of them ſhall from time to time make a true Account to the ſaid Juſtices of Peace, of the Receipts, Payments and Expences of the ſaid Sums of Mony, and if any of them refuſe ſo to do, then the Juſtices of Peace from time to time, by their Diſcretions, may make out Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs againſt the ſaid Collectors and Surveyors, their Executors and Adminiſtrators by Attach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, Precept or Warrant under their Hands and Seals returnable at their General S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ſſions of the Peace, and the ſaid Juſtices may allow ſuch reaſonable Coſts and Charge to the Surveyors and Collectors upon their Accounts, as to them ſhall ſeem convenient, 22. <hi>H.</hi> 8. <hi>c.</hi> 5. <hi>Dalt. I.</hi> P. <hi>c.</hi> 16. ibid.</p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="161" facs="tcp:96794:30"/>
If any ſuch Bridge be wholly in a City, or other Corporate Town, the Inhabitants of the ſaid City or Corporate Town muſt repair it; and where ſuch Bridges lie out of ſuch City or Corporate Town, the ſame muſt be made by the Inhabitants of the Shire or Riding within which the ſame Bridge ſhall be, and if part of the Bridge be in one Shire or Riding, City or Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porate Town, and part in another, then every of them ſhall be charged to make and repair ſuch part as ſhall lie, and be within their own Limits, 22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. <hi>c.</hi> 5. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. fol.</hi> 207. <hi>Dalt. I.</hi> P. <hi>c.</hi> 16. <hi>fol.</hi> 45.</p>
                     <p>But otherwiſe no Village or Freeman ſhall be compelled to make any Bridge; but ſuch as of old time, and by right they were wont to make, <hi>Magna Charta, c.</hi> 15.</p>
                     <p>By the Common Law, ſome Perſons were <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ound to repair Bridges, <hi>Ratione tenurae ſu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> Ter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>am,</hi> &amp;c. and this was binding, into whoſe Hinds ſoever the Eſtate did come; but they which have Lands on the one ſide, or on the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ther, or on both, are not bound in Common <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ight to repair the ſame, 44 <hi>El.</hi> 3. 31. 21 <hi>E.</hi> 4. 6. 5 <hi>H.</hi> 7. 3. <hi>Crompt.</hi> 186. 8 <hi>H.</hi> 7. 5. <hi>b. Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                              <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                           </gap>. f.</hi> 700.</p>
                     <p>If a Man which holdeth 100 Acres of Land, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>ght to repair a Bridge by tenure of the ſame, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>o allen 20 Acres thereof to one Man, and 10 <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>cres to another Man, in ſuch caſe every Owner <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Occupier of ſuch Lands muſt be charged <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>oportionably for their ſaid Lands, <hi>Regiſt.</hi> 268. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. <hi>N. B.</hi> 235. <hi>b. Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 700.</p>
                     <p>Again, Some by the Common Law were bound <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>y preſcription to repair a Bridge; but herein here is a diverſity between Bodies Politick or
<pb n="162" facs="tcp:96794:31"/>
Corporate, Spiritual or Temporal, and Natural Perſons: For Bodies Politick, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> may be bound by uſage and preſcription only, becauſe they are local, and have a perpetual Succeſſion, and never die; but a Natural Perſon cannot be bound by the Act of his Anceſtor, without Aſſets, or ſome Profit to be taken therefore, 21 <hi>E.</hi> 4. <hi>fol.</hi> 38. <hi>b.</hi> 27 <hi>Aſſ.</hi> 8. <hi>Crompt.</hi> 187. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, f.</hi> 700. <hi>Dalt. I.</hi> P. <hi>c.</hi> 16. <hi>f</hi> 45.</p>
                     <p>By Common Right, Bridges are to be amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the whole County, if it be not known who ought to do the ſame otherwiſe, <hi>Paſch.</hi> 19 <hi>E.</hi> 3. 28, 29. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inst. f.</hi> 701. <hi>Crompt.</hi> 186. <hi>b. Tr.</hi> 10 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. the Caſe of <hi>Longford</hi> Bridge, <hi>Rolls Caſes</hi> 1 <hi>part, f.</hi> 368. <hi>&amp; Cro. Rep.</hi> 3 <hi>part,</hi> the ſame Caſe.</p>
                     <p>If a Man erect a Mill for his own particular Profit, and cut a new Courſe for the Water to come to it, and makes a new Bridge over the ſame, and the Kings Subjects uſe to ride over the ſame as over a common Bridge; ſuch Bridge ought to be repaired by him who hath the Mill, and not by the County, becauſe he erected it for his own Benefit, 8 <hi>E.</hi> 2. <hi>B. R.</hi> ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judged for <hi>Bow</hi> Bridge and <hi>Channel</hi> Bridge a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Prior of <hi>Stratford, Rolls Caſes,</hi> 1 <hi>part, f.</hi> 368.</p>
                     <p>Such as are chargeable to repair a Bridge, may enter upon any other Mans Land or Soil ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyning, and lay their Stone, Lime, Timber or other Things neceſſary there, for the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pairing and amending thereof, and the Owner of the Lands ſhall have no Action therefore; for it is for the common Profit; and the Party that is chargeable to repair a Bridge, muſt alſo maintain the Way at each end thereof (thoug<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> the Soil be to another) and if the ends be broke<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <pb n="163" facs="tcp:96794:31"/>
by the Water-courſe, he muſt follow the Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter-courſe, and repair the Way, &amp;c. <hi>Crompt.</hi> 186. <hi>b.</hi> 43 <hi>Aſſ. Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 16. <hi>f.</hi> 46.</p>
                     <p>The Names of ſome Statutes for particular Bridges follow, 8 <hi>H.</hi> 6. <hi>c.</hi> 28. For the making of <hi>Burford</hi> and <hi>Culhamford</hi> Bridge. 18 <hi>E.</hi> 1. <hi>c.</hi> 7. &amp; 27 <hi>E. c.</hi> 25. For the maintenance of <hi>Rocheſter</hi> Bridge. 18 <hi>El. c.</hi> 20. For repair of the Bridges within a Mile of <hi>Oxford.</hi> 23 <hi>El. c.</hi> 11. For the maintenance of the Bridges over <hi>Toſſe</hi> in <hi>Wales.</hi> 39 <hi>El. c.</hi> 23. For making and repairing of <hi>New<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port</hi> and <hi>Carlion</hi> Bridges over the River <hi>Usk.</hi> 39 <hi>El. c.</hi> 24. For building and maintenance of a Bridge at <hi>Wilton</hi> upon <hi>Wy,</hi> near <hi>Roſs,</hi> in <hi>Hereford<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhire.</hi> 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 16. For erecting and repairing <hi>Edon</hi> and <hi>Presberk</hi> Bridges in <hi>Cumberland.</hi> 3 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 23. For making and repairing <hi>Chepſtow</hi> Bridge.</p>
                     <p>By the Stat. 22 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 12. It is Enacted, That the Surveyors and Orderers of the Work, of amendment of the High-ways, ſhall be year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly choſen in Chriſtmas Week, according to the Stat. 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M. c.</hi> 8. Which Perſons ſo choſen, ſhall take upon them that Office, and ſhall appoint ſix days for providing Stones, Gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vel, and other Materials, and for working in the High-ways, having reſpect to the Seaſon of the Year and Weather, and giving notice publickly ſome convenient time before the ſeveral days. At which day all Perſons liable to the ſaid Work, ſhall attend and work: And the ſaid Surveyors and Orderers ſhall make return of the Defaulters, and every of them within one Month, to ſome neighbouring Juſtice of the Peace of the ſame County.</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="directions">
                  <pb n="164" facs="tcp:96794:32"/>
                  <head>DIRECTIONS <hi>for the Keepers of Fairs and Markets.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>FAirs are accounted things of Franchiſe and Priviledge, as well as of Profit; and whether they be held and claimed by Charter of the King, or by Preſcription, which ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſes a former Charter, they ought to be hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den for no longer time, than ſuch Grant or Uſe will warrant: And after ſuch time, what is done there, is not warranted or juſtifiable, nor amounts to more than a private Tranſacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on; and the Sheriff ought to make Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, That thoſe that have Fairs keep them no longer then they ought to do; and every Lord of a Fair, ſhall at the beginning thereof, make Proclamation how long the ſame is to continue, upon pain to be grievouſly amerced to the King; And if they hold them longer than they ought, they ſhall be ſeiſed into the Kings Hands, until they make Fine for the Offence; and if a Merchant ſell Ware after the time the Fair ought to end, he ſhall forfeit to the King double the value of what is ſold, and the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecutor ſhall have the fourth part, <hi>Dalt. J. P. c.</hi> 62. <hi>f.</hi> 138.</p>
                  <p>The Owner, or Chief Keeper of every Fair and Market-over<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>, are to appoint and limit out a certain and open place within the Town, Place, Field or Circuit where Horſes, Mares, Geldings and Colts muſt be ſold, and they muſt appoint one ſufficient Perſon, or more, to take Toll, and keep the ſame place from ten
<pb n="165" facs="tcp:96794:32"/>
of the Clock before Noon, until Sun-ſet of every day of the foreſaid Fair or Market, upon pain to loſe for every Default 40 ſhillings, 2 &amp; 3 P. &amp; <hi>M. c.</hi> 7. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 715.</p>
                  <p>The Toll gatherer, his Deputy or Deputies are to take their due and lawful Tolls for every Horſe, Mare, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at the place and times afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid; and they are to have before them at the taking of the ſaid Toll, the Parties, to the Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, Exchange, Gift, Contract, or putting away of every ſuch Horſe, Mare, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and alſo the ſame Horſe, Mare, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſo ſold, exchanged, or put away, and then the Toll gatherer muſt write in his Book the Names, Sirnames, and dwelling Places of all the ſaid Parties, and the Colour, with one ſpecial Mark at the leaſt of the ſaid Horſe, Mare, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> on pain to forfeit for every Default 40 ſhillings, 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M. c.</hi> 7. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 7<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>5.</p>
                  <p>And the ſaid Toll gatherer is within one day after the Fair, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to bring his Book to the Owner, Governour or Ruler, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Fair or Market, who is then to cauſe a Note to be made out of the ſame; of the true number of all the Horſes, Mares, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſold at the ſaid Fair or Market, to which Note he muſt ſet his Hand or Mark, on pain of 40 ſhillings: And if the Toll-gatherer neglect to bring the Book, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>aid, he alſo forfeits 40 ſhillings, 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M. c.</hi> 7. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 715.</p>
                  <p>Where no Toll is due, the Book-keepers Fee for entring every Contract, is one penny and no more, 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M. c.</hi> 7. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 716.</p>
                  <p>Now ſince the making of this Stat 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> It is further provided by the 31 <hi>Eliz.</hi> That
<pb n="166" facs="tcp:96794:33"/>
every Seller or Exchanger of any Horſe, Mare, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in a Fair or Market, which is unknown to the Toll-taker or Book-keeper muſt procure one credible Perſon that is well known to the Toll-keeper, or Book-keeper, who is to vouch and teſtifie his Knowledge of the Seller, and the Toll-taker, or Book keeper, is to enter both the Names and Sirnames, Myſteries, and Places of Dwelling of the Seller and Voucher into his Book, with the Colour, Mark and Price of the Horſe, Mare, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſo ſold or exchanged; and he is to give the Buyer, if he require it, a Note in writing out of his Book, concerning the Contract ſubſcribed with his Hand, for which he is to have two pence, 31 <hi>El. c.</hi> 12. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 717, 718.</p>
                  <p>Every Toll-taker or Book-keeper that ſuffers a Sale to paſs without a Voucher, unleſs he know the Party of his own Knowledge, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, and every Perſon making falſe Teſtimony or Avouchment in the behalf aforeſaid, and every Seller unknown to the Toll-taker, not bringing a Voucher, and cauſing the ſame to be entred as aforeſaid, forfeits five pounds, one Moiety thereof to the King, and the other to the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecutor; and alſo the ſale of ſuch Horſe, Mare, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to be void, 31 <hi>El. c.</hi> 12. <hi>Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 718.</p>
                  <p>And note, That though an Horſe, Mare, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> be at the ſale uſed in all the Points aforeſaid, with Voucher, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> yet the right Owner, his Executors or Adminiſtrators, may redeem a ſtoln Horſe, if they claim him within ſix months after the ſtealing, at the Pariſh or Corporation, where they ſhall find him and make proof within 40 days after, by two ſufficient Witneſſes, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore
<pb n="167" facs="tcp:96794:33"/>
the next Juſtice of Peace of the County, or before the Head Officer in a Corporation, that the Horſe was theirs, and repay to the Buyer ſuch price for the Horſe, as the ſame Buyer ſhall upon his own Oath before ſuch Juſtice or Officer, teſtifie he paid for him, 31 <hi>El. c.</hi> 12. <hi>wingates Stat. Tit. Fairs and Markets, Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 718.</p>
                  <p>If a ſtoln Horſe be not ſold in Fair or Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket, according to the Rules aforeſaid, then ſuch Sale does not alter the Property of the right Owner, but he may ſeize or replevy him where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever he finds him, 31 <hi>El. c. Wingate ubi ſupra, Co.</hi> 2 <hi>part, Inſt. f.</hi> 718.</p>
                  <p>No Perſon ſhall buy any Oxen, Ronts, Steers, Kine, Heifers, Calves, Sheep, Lambs, Goats or Kids alive, and ſell the ſame again, unleſs he keep the ſame five Weeks in his own Grounds; or where he hath Herbage by Grant or Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcription, upon pain to loſe double the value of the Cattle; one Moiety to the King, the other to the Informer, 5 <hi>Ed.</hi> 6. <hi>c.</hi> 14.</p>
                  <p>By the Stat. 22 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 8. There ſhall be no Buſhel but the <hi>Wincheſter</hi> Buſhel, containing eight Gallons, and none ſhall ſell by other Meaſure, on pain of 40 ſhillings.</p>
                  <p>If the Clerk of the Market of the Kings Houſe, or others authorized to mark or ſeal Meaſures, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>eing required, ſhall neglect or refuſe to ſeal or mark any Buſhel, Half Buſhel, or Peck duly gauged, he forfeirs 5 <hi>l.</hi> for the firſt Offence, and for every other Offence 10 <hi>l.</hi> or if the Kings Clerk of the Market of his Houſe take more than his Fees, or if any other take above one peny for ſealing a Buſhel, one half peny for the Half Buſhel or Peck, or more than one farthing for
<pb n="168" facs="tcp:96794:34"/>
any leſſer Meaſure, he incurs the Penalties in the Stat. 17 <hi>Car.</hi> 1.</p>
                  <p>That at the charge of ſuch Perſons who have the Toll, or profit of the Market where no Toll is taken, there ſhall be before 29 <hi>Sept.</hi> 1670. one Meaſure of Braſs provided and chained in the Market-place, upon pain to forfeit 5 <hi>l.</hi> 22 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 8.</p>
                  <p>By the Stat. of 22 &amp; 23 <hi>Car</hi> 2. It is further provided, That whoſoever ſhall ſell or buy any Corn or Salt by the Bag, or without meaſuring, being thereunto required, or in any other man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner than as by the Stat. 22 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 8. is direct<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and without ſhaking the Meaſure by the Buyer, ſhall forfeit beſides the Penalty in the former Act, all the Corn or Salt, or the value therefore to the Perſon or Perſons complaining, 22 &amp; 23 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 12.</p>
                  <p>Upon complaint to one or more Juſtices of Peace, the Proof ſhall lie upon the Defendant, to make appear by Oath of one or more Witneſſes, that he or they did ſell or buy according to this and the ſaid former Act; wherein if he fail, he ſhall forfeit as by this Act is directed, to be le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vied by diſtreſs and ſale of Goods, by Warrant under the Hand and Seal of one or more Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices before whom ſuch Conviction ſhall be. The Penalties to be diſtributed, one half to the Poor of the Pariſh where the Offence ſhall be committed, the other to the Informer, 22 &amp; 23 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 12.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="directions">
                  <pb n="169" facs="tcp:96794:34"/>
                  <head>DIRECTIONS <hi>to Treaſurers, for the Relief of Poor Maimed Soldiers and Mariners.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THE Juſtices of Peace are yearly at the Quarter Seſſions, about <hi>Eaſter,</hi> to chooſe or appoint one or two Perſons (according to their Diſcretions) of the County, for the taking and diſtributing of the Monies collected for the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ief of poor maimed Soldiers and Mariners: And theſe Treaſurers, by the Words of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ture, ought to be Subſidy Men of 10 pounds <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> Lands, or 15 pounds in Goods, and theſe officers are to continue in their Office one Year, and new ones then to be choſen in their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ooms, 43 <hi>El c.</hi> 3. <hi>Wingates Stat. Tit. Captains.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>Now for the raiſing of Mony for theſe Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurers, the greater part of the Juſtices in their Quarter Seſſions, have power to charge every Pariſh within their Limits, towards a Weekly <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>elief of maimed Soldiers and Mariners, ſo <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hat no Pariſh pay Weekly above 10 pence, no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nder 2 pence; nor any County, which conſiſts <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>f above 50 Pariſhes, pay above 6 pence, one <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ariſh with another, 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 3.</p>
                  <p>When the Tax is levied, the Conſtables and Churchwardens are to deliver it quarterly (ten days before every Quarter Seſſions) to the High Conſtables of their Diviſion, who muſt deliver to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>e Treaſurers of the County, at the ſame Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>er Seſſions all the ſame Mony; and if the Conſtables or Churchwardens, their Executors, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> fail in the payment, to the High Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble,
<pb n="170" facs="tcp:96794:35"/>
within the time aforeſaid, then they are to forfeit 20 <hi>s.</hi> and if the High Conſtable fall to pay the Treaſurers every Seſſions, then he forfeits 40 <hi>s.</hi> which Forfeitures, as it ſeems, the Treaſurers may levy by Diſtreſs and Sale of the Offenders Goods, without any Warrant, rendring the overplus to the Owner: And theſe Forfeitures are to go in Augmentation of the Treaſurers Stock, 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 3.</p>
                  <p>The maimed Soldier or Mariner which was Preſt, ſhall repair (if he be able to Travel) to the Treaſurers of the County where he was Preſt; if he were not Preſt, then to the Treaſurers of the County where he was Born, or were he laſt dwelt by the ſpace of three years, at his Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction; but if he be not able to Travel, then to the Treaſurers of the County where he Lands; and he is to bring with him a Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate under the Hand and Seal of the Chief Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mander, or of the Captain under whom he ſerved, containing the particular of his Hurts and Service, which Certificate ſhall alſo be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed by the Muſter-Maſter, or the Receiver-General of the Rolls for the Muſter, under one of their Hands, 33 <hi>El. c.</hi> 3.</p>
                  <p>Then upon ſuch a Certificate, the Treaſurer aforeſaid may allow the Party Relief to main<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tain him till the next Quarter Seſſions; and then the major-part of the Juſtices may allo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> him a Penſion, which the Treaſurers mu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> pay him quarterly, until it ſhall be revoked o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> altered by the ſaid Juſtices; and this Allowanc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> is not to exceed 10 <hi>l. per annum</hi> to a Commo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> Soldier, nor 15 <hi>l.</hi> to an Officer under a Lieu<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tenant, nor 20 <hi>l.</hi> to a Lieutenant, 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <hi>Wingates Stat. Tit. Captains and Soldiers.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <pb n="171" facs="tcp:96794:35"/>
Where Soldiers and Mariners arrive far from the place where they are to receive Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lief, the Treaſurers there ſhall give them Relief, and a Teſtimonial whereby they may paſs from Treaſurer to Treaſurer, until they ſhall come to the place required; and this ſhall be done upon the bare Certificate of the Commander and Captain, although they have not as yet obtain'd any Allowance from the Muſter-Maſter, or Receiver-General of the Muſter-Rolls, <hi>Win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gates Stat. Tit. Captains and Soldiers,</hi> 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 3.</p>
                  <p>If any Soldier or Mariner beg, or counterfeit <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> Certificate, he ſhall be puniſhed as a Common Rogue, and ſhall loſe his Penſion, if he have any 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 3. <hi>Wingate, ut ſupra.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>When out of the County where the Party was Preſt, a fit Penſion cannot be ſatisfied, it ſhall then be ſupplied by the County where he was born, or elſe where he laſt dwelt by the ſpace of three years, <hi>Wingate, ubi ſupra,</hi> 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 3.</p>
                  <p>The Treaſurers are to Regiſter all their Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipts and Disburſements, and muſt enter the Names of the Parties relieved into their Book, and alſo the Certificate, by virtue whereof the Disburſements are made; and where they diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>allow of a Certificate, they are to ſet down <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>he Reaſons of their Refuſal under the Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate, or on the back thereof, 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 3. <hi>Win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gate Stat. Tit. Captains and Soldiers.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>If any Treaſurer wilfully refuſe to give Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lief in the Caſes aforeſaid, the Juſtices of the Peace, in their Seſſions, may ſet a Fine upon him, which may be levied by Diſtreſs and Sale of his Goods, <hi>Wingate, ubi ſupra.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <pb n="172" facs="tcp:96794:36"/>
Theſe Officers at the end of their Year, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in 10 days after <hi>Eaſter</hi> Seſſions, are to give u<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> a juſt Account to the ſucceeding Treaſurers o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> all their Receipts and Disburſements within the time of their Office; and then if they have any Mony in their Hands, they are to deliver it to their Succeſſors; and if any ſuch Officer<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> his Executors or Adminiſtrators ſhall not giv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> up ſuch Account within the time aforeſaid, o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> ſhall be otherwiſe negligent in the Executio<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> of his Office; The Juſtice<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> at the Seſſions ma<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> aſſeſs what Fine they pleaſe upon him; ſo tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> it be not under five pounds, but what the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> pleaſe above five pounds upon him, his Exe<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cutors or Adminiſtrators, <hi>Wingate, ubi ſupra</hi> 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 3.</p>
                  <p>In Corporations, the Juſtices there are t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> put this Act in Execution, and not the Ju<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſtices of the County: This Act is not to pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>hibit the City of <hi>London</hi> to make a Tax if ne<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> require, differing from that above limited i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> this Act, ſo that no Pariſh pay above thre<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> ſhillings Weekly, nor under twelve pen<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> Weekly, one Pariſh with another, 43 <hi>El. c.</hi> 3.</p>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
                  <pb facs="tcp:96794:36"/>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
      </group>
   </text>
</TEI>
